<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mbeans on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/mbeans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mbeans on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/mbeans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE Systems Management - dodgy counter behaviour</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/08/obiee-systems-management-dodgy-counter-behaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/08/obiee-systems-management-dodgy-counter-behaviour/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of exploring of OBIEE Systems Management data, covered in a mini-series of blog posts, Collecting OBIEE systems management data.
There are a vast number of counters exposed, ranging from the very interesting (Active Sessions, Cache Hits, etc) to the less so (Total Query Piggybacks, although for some seriously hardcore performance tuning even this may be of interest).
This short blog post is about a couple of counters which I&amp;rsquo;ve been monitoring but which looks to not be entirely reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting OBIEE systems management data with jmx</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/collecting-obiee-systems-management-data-with-jmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/collecting-obiee-systems-management-data-with-jmx/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the first part of three detailed articles making up a mini-series about OBIEE monitoring. It demonstrates how to capture OBIEE performance information, and optionally graph it out and serve it through an auto-updating webpage.
For some background on OBIEE&amp;rsquo;s Systems Management component, along with JMX and MBeans, see here and here. The following assumes you know your mbeans from coffee beans and jmx from a bmx.
The metric collection is built around the jmxsh tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE monitoring</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/obiee-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/obiee-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who read my blog regularly may have noticed I have a slight obsession with the OBIEE systems management capability which is exposed through JMX. Venkat has blogged this week about JMX in OBI11g, and it&amp;rsquo;s clearly a technology worth understanding properly. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been tinkering with how to make use of it for monitoring purposes, most recently using JConsole and discussed here. What follows is an extension of this idea, cobbled together with a bit of shell scripting, awk, gnuplot, and sticky backed plastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle BI Management / Systems Management MBeans</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/22/oracle-bi-management-/-systems-management-mbeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/22/oracle-bi-management-/-systems-management-mbeans/</guid>
      <description>Part of looking at the various gubbins inside OBIEE led me to realise that the Oracle BI Management application drives quite a few things. It exposes MBeans (Management Beans, a java term), accessible through jmx. In the installation of OBIEE this component is referred to as &amp;ldquo;Systems Management&amp;rdquo;.
The MBeans give us real-time performance information, along with access to all the configuration options that are normally done through config files (instanceconfig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE admin tools &amp;amp; hacks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/obiee-admin-tools-amp-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/obiee-admin-tools-amp-hacks/</guid>
      <description>As a kid I loved the idea of lego where you can disassemble and reassemble something from the ground up. As soon as I got my hands on a computer it was the same. You can have your Acorn Archimedes with its games, where do I find the sprites and sound files behind it? Likewise Microsoft Word, let me at the VBA underneath to hack it around and see what else it can do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
