<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>google on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in google on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Googling for OBIEE information</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/03/advanced-googling-for-obiee-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/03/advanced-googling-for-obiee-information/</guid>
      <description>Want to find all PDFs from Oracle about OBIEE?

There&amp;rsquo;s some interesting ones that this turned up on Oracle&amp;rsquo;s public FTP. In particular:
 BI EE Environmental and Multi-User Development Migration Processes Securing Oracle BI Enterprise Edition  (There&amp;rsquo;s also PowerPoint files on there including this one but Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to index them)
You can use Google&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Search page to build similar queries:
You can also use Google Alerts so that any time a new entry matching your search criteria is added in Google&amp;rsquo;s index you get notified of it either by email or on an RSS feed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google vs Bing</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/05/google-vs-bing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/05/google-vs-bing/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of hype about Bing recently, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try it out in trying to get to the bottom of this question on the OBIEE forum.
The question was around the nqschangepassword utility and the error it&amp;rsquo;s reporting: nQSError: 46090 The odbc.ini file could not found or could not be accessed.
I did a google for the error to see what other issues could cause the error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google and Korean OTN forums</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/02/google-and-korean-otn-forums/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/02/google-and-korean-otn-forums/</guid>
      <description>Why does Google more often than not return the korean (kr) version of OTN forums for a match, but not english?
If I search Google for &amp;ldquo;Send notification:&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;oracle.ons.Notification&amp;rdquo; the top hit is for kr.forums.oracle.com/forums/thread.jspa?threadID=650662
If you strip the kr from the URL you get this, which makes more sense given the locality when doing the search in Google.
Only mildly irritating, but odd behaviour nonetheless</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
