<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markdown on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 08:59:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Authoring Wordpress blogs in Markdown (with Google Docs for review)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2023/05/03/authoring-wordpress-blogs-in-markdown-with-google-docs-for-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 08:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2023/05/03/authoring-wordpress-blogs-in-markdown-with-google-docs-for-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wordpress still, to an extent, rules the blogging world. Its longevity is testament to…something about it ;) However, it&amp;rsquo;s not my favourite platform in which to write a blog by a long way. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t support Markdown to the extent that I want. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the plugins; no, they didn&amp;rsquo;t do what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like to write all my content in a structured format - ideally &lt;a href=&#34;https://asciidoc.org/&#34;&gt;Asciidoc&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2017/09/12/what-is-markdown-and-why-is-it-awesome/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll settle for Markdown too&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I stayed [almost] sane whilst composing a blog in Markdown, reviewing it in Google Docs, and then publishing it in Wordpress in a non-lossy way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Ghost to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;_why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been blogging for quite a few years now, starting on Blogger, soon onto &lt;a href=&#34;https://rnm1978.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, and then to Ghost a couple of years ago. Blogger was fairly lame, WP yucky, but I really do like Ghost. It’s simple and powerful and was &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; for my needs. My needs being, an outlet for technical content that respected formatting, worked with a markup language (Markdown), and didn’t &lt;em&gt;f**k things up&lt;/em&gt; in the way that WP often would in its WYSIWYG handling of content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Markdown, and Why is it Awesome?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2017/09/12/what-is-markdown-and-why-is-it-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2017/09/12/what-is-markdown-and-why-is-it-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a plain-text formatting syntax. It enables you write documents in plain text, readable by others in plain text, and optionally rendered into nicely formatted PDF, HTML, DOCX etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s used widely in software documentation, particularly open-source, because it enables richer formatting than plain-text alone, but without constraining authors or readers to a given software platform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Platforms such as github natively support Markdown rendering - so you write your &lt;code&gt;README&lt;/code&gt; etc in markdown, and when viewed on github it is automagically rendered - without you needing to actually do anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
