<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>asciidoc on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/asciidoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in asciidoc on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 09:00:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/asciidoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Including content from external links with Asciidoc in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/09/18/including-content-from-external-links-with-asciidoc-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 09:00:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/09/18/including-content-from-external-links-with-asciidoc-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I use Hugo for my blog, hosted on GitHub pages. One of the reasons I’m really happy with it is that I can use Asciidoc to author my posts. I was writing a blog recently in which I wanted to include some code that’s hosted on GitHub. I could have copied &amp;amp; pasted it into the blog but that would be lame!
 With Asciidoc you can use the include:: directive to include both local files:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting from AsciiDoc to Google Docs and MS Word</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/04/16/converting-from-asciidoc-to-google-docs-and-ms-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:27:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/04/16/converting-from-asciidoc-to-google-docs-and-ms-word/</guid>
      <description>Updated 16 April 2020 to cover formatting tricks &amp;amp; add import to Google Docs info
 Short and sweet this one. I’ve written in the past how I love Markdown but I’ve actually moved on from that and now firmly throw my hat in the AsciiDoc ring. I’ll write another post another time explaining why in more detail, but in short it’s just more powerful whilst still simple and readable without compilation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Ghost to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Why? I’ve been blogging for quite a few years now, starting on Blogger, soon onto WordPress, and then to Ghost a couple of years ago. Blogger was fairly lame, WP yucky, but I really do like Ghost. It’s simple and powerful and was perfect for my needs. My needs being, an outlet for technical content that respected formatting, worked with a markup language (Markdown), and didn’t f**k things up in the way that WP often would in its WYSIWYG handling of content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
