<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asciidoc on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/asciidoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asciidoc on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 12:05:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/asciidoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disabling Vale Linting Selectively in Asciidoc</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2024/12/11/disabling-vale-linting-selectively-in-asciidoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 12:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2024/12/11/disabling-vale-linting-selectively-in-asciidoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m a &lt;strong&gt;HUGE&lt;/strong&gt; fan of Docs as Code in general, and specifically tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://vale.sh&#34;&gt;Vale&lt;/a&gt; that lint your prose for adherence to style rule.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing that had been bugging me though was how to selectively disable Vale for particular sections of a document.&#xA;Usually linting issues should be addressed at root: either fix the prose, or update the style rule. Either it’s a rule, or it’s not, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes though I’ve found a need to make a particular exception to a rule, or simply needed to skip linting for a particular file.&#xA;I was struggling with how to do this in Asciidoc.&#xA;Despite &lt;a href=&#34;https://vale.sh/docs/topics/config/#asciidoc&#34;&gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt; showing how to, I could never get it to work reliably.&#xA;Now I’ve taken some time to dig into it, I think I’ve finally understood :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Including content from external links with Asciidoc in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/09/18/including-content-from-external-links-with-asciidoc-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 09:00:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/09/18/including-content-from-external-links-with-asciidoc-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for my blog, hosted on GitHub pages. One of the reasons I’m really happy with it is that I can use Asciidoc to author my posts. I was writing a blog recently in which I wanted to include some code that’s hosted on GitHub. I could have copied &amp;amp; pasted it into the blog but that would be lame!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Asciidoc you can use the &lt;code&gt;include::&lt;/code&gt; directive to include both local files:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting from AsciiDoc to Google Docs and MS Word</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/04/16/converting-from-asciidoc-to-google-docs-and-ms-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:27:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/04/16/converting-from-asciidoc-to-google-docs-and-ms-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated 16 April 2020 to cover formatting tricks &amp;amp; add import to Google Docs info&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Short and sweet this one. I’ve written in the past how&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2017/09/12/what-is-markdown-and-why-is-it-awesome/&#34;&gt;I&#xA;love Markdown&lt;/a&gt; but I’ve actually moved on from that and now firmly throw&#xA;my hat in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.methods.co.nz/asciidoc/&#34;&gt;AsciiDoc&lt;/a&gt; ring. I’ll&#xA;write another post another time explaining why in more detail, but in&#xA;short it’s just more powerful whilst still simple and readable without&#xA;compilation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So anyway, I use AsciiDoc (adoc) for all my technical (and often&#xA;non-technical) writing now, and from there usually dump it out to HTML&#xA;which I can share with people as needed:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Ghost to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;_why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been blogging for quite a few years now, starting on Blogger, soon onto &lt;a href=&#34;https://rnm1978.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, and then to Ghost a couple of years ago. Blogger was fairly lame, WP yucky, but I really do like Ghost. It’s simple and powerful and was &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; for my needs. My needs being, an outlet for technical content that respected formatting, worked with a markup language (Markdown), and didn’t &lt;em&gt;f**k things up&lt;/em&gt; in the way that WP often would in its WYSIWYG handling of content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
