<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>presentation on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in presentation on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing and OBIEE</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/24/performance-testing-and-obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/24/performance-testing-and-obiee/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my presentation &amp;ldquo;Performance Testing and OBIEE&amp;rdquo; that I gave at the RittmanMead BI Forum 2010: Performance Testing and OBIEE.pptx
It&amp;rsquo;s a Powerpoint 2007 file (pptx) for which you may need the Microsoft PowerPoint Viewer 2007. I&amp;rsquo;ve included copious notes on each slide which hopefully cover the gist of what I talked about when I was delivering it. There are also a handful of funky animations which is why I&amp;rsquo;ve left it in pptx and not exported to PDF or other format (sorry Open Office users).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first presentation - afterthoughts</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/23/my-first-presentation-afterthoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/23/my-first-presentation-afterthoughts/</guid>
      <description>I delivered my first presentation today, at the RittmanMead BI Forum.I was really nervous in the hours and minutes leading up to it, but once I got up there and started talking I actually quite enjoyed it. If you were in the audience, I&amp;rsquo;d love some feedback in the comments section below, particularly any &amp;ldquo;constructive criticism&amp;rdquo;. I obviously didn&amp;rsquo;t make too much of a mess of it, as I was awarded &amp;ldquo;best speaker&amp;rdquo; of the event, which was a great honour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RittmanMead BI Forum 2010</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/21/rittmanmead-bi-forum-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/21/rittmanmead-bi-forum-2010/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just returned from the RittmanMead 2010 BI Forum which this year was at the Seattle Hotel in Brighton Marina.
The event was limited to 50 attendees, and I think this was a good number. The event was explicitly pitched at a very technical expert level, and the audience very much represented this. Whereas at a larger conference you may find the odd manager wandering around pretending to be technical ;-) this event was most definitely not pitched at such types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first presentation - help!</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/04/21/my-first-presentation-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/04/21/my-first-presentation-help/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m doing my first ever conference presentation next month at the 2010 Rittman Mead BI Forum.
My presentation is called Performance Testing OBIEE, which is something I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time working on over the last few months. I think the challenge is going to be distilling it all into a session that&amp;rsquo;s not going to overwhelm everyone or bore them to death! Well, actually, the challenge is going to be the presenting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
