<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHub Actions on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/github-actions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHub Actions on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 08:54:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/github-actions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Docs - Automating Jekyll Builds and Link Checking for PRs</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2023/04/20/building-better-docs-automating-jekyll-builds-and-link-checking-for-prs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 08:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2023/04/20/building-better-docs-automating-jekyll-builds-and-link-checking-for-prs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most important ways that a project can help its developers is providing them good documentation. Actually, scratch that. &lt;em&gt;Great&lt;/em&gt; documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub Actions to build automagic Hugo previews of draft articles</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/06/using-github-actions-to-build-automagic-hugo-previews-of-draft-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/06/using-github-actions-to-build-automagic-hugo-previews-of-draft-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog is written in Asciidoc, built using Hugo, and hosted on GitHub Pages. I recently wanted to share the draft of a post I was writing with someone and ended up exporting a local preview to a PDF - not a great workflow! This blog post shows you how to create an automagic hosted preview of any draft content on Hugo using GitHub Actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is useful for previewing and sharing one’s own content, but also for making good use of GitHub as a collaborative platform - if someone &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rmoff/rmoff-blog/pull/4#pullrequestreview-933907051&#34;&gt;reviews and amends your PR&lt;/a&gt; the post gets updated in the preview too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling Hugo Builds on GitHub pages with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/20/scheduling-hugo-builds-on-github-pages-with-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 23:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/20/scheduling-hugo-builds-on-github-pages-with-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve used various blogging platforms; after a brief dalliance with Blogger I started for real with the near-inevitable Wordpress.com. From there I decided it would be fun to self-host using Ghost, and then almost &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;exactly two years ago to the day&lt;/a&gt; decided it definitely was not fun to spend time patching and upgrading my blog platform instead of writing blog articles, so headed over to my current platform of choice: Hugo hosted on GitHub pages. This has worked extremely well for me during that time, doing everything I want from it until recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
