<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 13:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Try To Keep Up With The Data Tech World (A List of Data Blogs)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2024/05/22/how-i-try-to-keep-up-with-the-data-tech-world-a-list-of-data-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 13:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2024/05/22/how-i-try-to-keep-up-with-the-data-tech-world-a-list-of-data-blogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do my best to try and keep, if not abreast of, then at least aware of what’s going on in the world of data. That includes RDBMS, Event streaming, stream processing, open source data projects, data engineering, object storage, and more. If you’re interested in the same, then you might find this blog useful, because I’m sharing my sources :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick profiling of data in Apache Kafka using kafkacat and visidata</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2021/03/04/quick-profiling-of-data-in-apache-kafka-using-kafkacat-and-visidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 14:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2021/03/04/quick-profiling-of-data-in-apache-kafka-using-kafkacat-and-visidata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ksqlDB is a fantastically powerful tool for processing and analysing streams of data in Apache Kafka. But sometimes, you just want a quick way to profile the data in a topic in Kafka. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2021/02/02/performing-a-group-by-on-data-in-bash/&#34;&gt;wrote about this previously&lt;/a&gt; with a convoluted (but effective) set of bash commands pipelined together to perform a &lt;code&gt;GROUP BY&lt;/code&gt; on data. Then someone introduced me to &lt;code&gt;visidata&lt;/code&gt;, which makes it all a lot quicker!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Up with the Deluge</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2017/03/11/keeping-up-with-the-deluge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2017/03/11/keeping-up-with-the-deluge/</guid>
      <description>How do you try and stay current on technical affairs, given only 24 hours in a day and a job to do as well? Here&amp;rsquo;s my take on it&amp;hellip;
One of the many things that has changed perceptibly since the beginning of this century when I started working in IT is the amount of information freely available, and being created all the time. Back then, printed books and manuals were still the primary source of definitive information about a piece of software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
