<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devrel on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.github.io/categories/devrel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devrel on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 23:38:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rmoff.github.io/categories/devrel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying sane on the road as a Developer Advocate</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/09/19/staying-sane-on-the-road-as-a-developer-advocate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 23:38:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/09/19/staying-sane-on-the-road-as-a-developer-advocate/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been a full-time Developer Advocate for nearly 1.5 years now, and have learnt lots along the way. The stuff I&amp;#8217;ve learnt about being an advocate I&amp;#8217;ve written about elsewhere (here/here/here); today I want to write about something that&amp;#8217;s just as important: staying sane and looking after yourself whilst on the road. This is also tangentially related to another of my favourite posts that I&amp;#8217;ve written: Travelling for Work, with Kids at Home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I&#39;ll be on the road for the remainder of 2019</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 17:36:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had a relaxing couple of weeks off work over the summer, and came back today to realise that I&amp;#8217;ve got a fair bit of conference and meetup travel to wrap my head around for the next few months :)
 If you&amp;#8217;re interested in where I&amp;#8217;ll be and want to come and say hi, hear about Kafka—or just grab a coffee or beer, herewith my itinerary as it currently stands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts on Not Making a Crap Slide Deck</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/03/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-making-a-crap-slide-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 10:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/03/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-making-a-crap-slide-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is the companion to an earlier one that I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/&#34;&gt;conference abstracts&lt;/a&gt;. In the same way that the last one was inspired by reviewing a ton of abstracts and noticing a recurring pattern in my suggestions, so this one comes from reviewing a bunch of slide decks for a forthcoming conference. They all look like good talks, but in several cases &lt;em&gt;these great talks are fighting to get out from underneath the deadening weight of slides&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herewith follows my highly-opinionated, fairly-subjective, and extremely-terse advice and general suggestions for slide decks. You can also find relating ramblings in &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.github.io/2019/03/01/preparing-a-new-talk/&#34;&gt;this recent post&lt;/a&gt; too. My friend and colleague Vik Gamov also wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamov.io/posts/2019/03/15/quick-tips-on-designing-your-next-presentation.html&#34;&gt;a good post&lt;/a&gt; on this same topic, and linked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://player.oreilly.com/videos/9781491954980&#34;&gt;a good video&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;#8217;d recommend you watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing a New Talk</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/03/01/preparing-a-new-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 11:00:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/03/01/preparing-a-new-talk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve written quite a few talks over the years, but usually as a side-line to my day job. In my role as a Developer Advocate, talks are part of What I Do, and so I can dedicate more time to it. A lot of the talks I&amp;#8217;ve done previously have evolved through numerous iterations, and with a new talk to deliver for the &#34;Spring Season&#34; of conferences, I thought it would be interesting to track what it took from concept to actual delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling for Work, with Kids at Home</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/02/09/travelling-for-work-with-kids-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 14:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2019/02/09/travelling-for-work-with-kids-at-home/</guid>
      <description>I began travelling for my job when my first child was three months old. But don&amp;#8217;t mistake correlation for causation…it wasn&amp;#8217;t the broken nights&#39; sleep that forced me onto the road, but an excellent job opportunity that seemed worth the risk. Nearly eight years later and I&amp;#8217;m in a different job but still with a bunch of travel involved. How much I travel has varied. It&amp;#8217;s tended to average around 30%, but has peaked at way more than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts on Not Writing a Crap Abstract</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 22:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.github.io/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve reviewed a bunch of abstracts in the last couple of days, here are some common suggestions I made:
   No need to include your company name in the abstract text. Chances are I&amp;#8217;ve not heard of your company, and even if I have, what does it add to my comprehension of your abstract and what you&amp;#8217;re going to talk about? Possible exception would be the &#34;hot&#34; tech companies where people will see a talk just because it&amp;#8217;s Netflix etc</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>