<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevRel on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/devrel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DevRel on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 10:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/devrel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Write more blogs articles, not fewer (Don&#39;t leave the scraps on the cutting floor)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2025/03/11/write-more-blogs-articles-not-fewer-dont-leave-the-scraps-on-the-cutting-floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 10:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2025/03/11/write-more-blogs-articles-not-fewer-dont-leave-the-scraps-on-the-cutting-floor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some would say that the perfect blog article takes the reader on a journey on in which the development process looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://rmoff.net/images/2025/03/blog_content1.excalidraw.webp&#34; alt=&#34;blog content1.excalidraw&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Writing for Developers</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2023/07/19/blog-writing-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 20:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2023/07/19/blog-writing-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is one of the most powerful forms of communication, and it’s useful in a multitude of roles and contexts. As a &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net&#34;&gt;blog-writing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/treeverse/lakeFS/pulls?q=is%3Apr+label%3Adocs+author%3Armoff+&#34;&gt;documentation-authoring&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rmoff/status/1587382202781913089&#34;&gt;twitter-shitposting&lt;/a&gt; DevEx engineer I spend a lot of my time writing. Recently, someone paid me a very nice compliment about a blog I’d written and asked how they could learn to write like me and what resources I’d recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never one to miss a chance to write and share something, here’s my response to this :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does This DevEx Engineer Do?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2023/05/23/what-does-this-devex-engineer-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 23:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2023/05/23/what-does-this-devex-engineer-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was originally titled more broadly &amp;ldquo;What Does &lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; DevEx Engineer Do&amp;rdquo;, but that made it into a far too tedious and long-winding etymological exploration of the discipline. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you what this particular instantiation of the entity does 😄&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Forwards, and Looking Backwards</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/12/09/looking-forwards-and-looking-backwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/12/09/looking-forwards-and-looking-backwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we enter December and 2022 draws to a close, so does a significant chapter in my working career—later this month I’ll be leaving Confluent and onto pastures new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s nearly six years since I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2017/03/10/time-for-a-change/&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;moving on&amp;#39; blog entry&lt;/a&gt;, and as well as sharing what I’ll be working on next (and why), I also want to reflect on how much I’ve benefited from my time at Confluent and particularly the people with whom I worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Sausage Factory: How we Built the Program for Current 2022</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/inside-the-sausage-factory-how-we-built-the-program-for-current-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 12:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/inside-the-sausage-factory-how-we-built-the-program-for-current-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been to a conference, particularly as a speaker whose submitted a paper that may or may not have been accepted, you might wonder quite how conferences choose the talks that get accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of chairing the program committee for Current and Kafka Summit this year and curating the final program for both. Here’s a glimpse behind the curtains of how we built the program for Current 2022. It was originally posted as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rmoff/status/1549410161688813569&#34;&gt;thread on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>⚡️ Writing an abstract for a lightning talk ⚡️</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/%EF%B8%8F-writing-an-abstract-for-a-lightning-talk-%EF%B8%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/%EF%B8%8F-writing-an-abstract-for-a-lightning-talk-%EF%B8%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rmoff/status/1544257707049467905&#34;&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are generally 5-10 minutes. As the name implies - they are quick!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good lightning talk is not just your breakout talk condensed into a shorter time frame. You can’t simply deliver the same material faster, or the same material at a higher level, or the same material with a few bits left out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Good Tech Conference Abstract - Learn from the Mistakes of Others</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/07/20/how-to-write-a-good-tech-conference-abstract-learn-from-the-mistakes-of-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 08:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/07/20/how-to-write-a-good-tech-conference-abstract-learn-from-the-mistakes-of-others/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the program for any conference is not an easy task. There will always be a speaker disappointed that their talk didn’t get in—or perhaps an audience who are disappointed that a particular talk &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; get in. As the chair of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.confluent.io/en-gb/blog/introducing-current-2022-program-committee/&#34;&gt;program committee&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.currentevent.io/&#34;&gt;Current 22&lt;/a&gt; one of the things that I’ve found really useful in building out the program this time round are the comments that the program committee left against submissions as they reviewed them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some common patterns I saw, and I thought it would be useful to share these here. Perhaps you’re an aspiring conference speaker looking to understand what mistakes to avoid. Maybe you’re an existing speaker whose abstracts don’t get accepted as often as you’d like. Or perhaps you’re just curious as to what goes on behind the curtains :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote-First Developer Advocacy</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/07/remote-first-developer-advocacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 21:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/07/remote-first-developer-advocacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced that a developer advocate &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be effective remotely. As a profession, we’ve all spent two years figuring out how to do just that. Some of it worked out great. Some of it, less so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2022/04/07/hanging-up-my-boarding-passes-and-jetlagfor-now/&#34;&gt;made the decision&lt;/a&gt; during COVID to stop travelling as part of my role as a developer advocate. In this article, I talk about my experience with different areas of advocacy done remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hanging up my Boarding Passes and Jetlag…for now</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/07/hanging-up-my-boarding-passes-and-jetlagfor-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 20:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/07/hanging-up-my-boarding-passes-and-jetlagfor-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently started writing an abstract for a conference later this year and realised that I’m not even sure if I want to do it. Not the conference—it’s a great one—but just the whole up on stage doing a talk thing. I can’t work out if this is just nerves from the amount of time off the stage, or something more fundamental to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life as a Developer Advocate, nine months into a pandemic</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/03/life-as-a-developer-advocate-nine-months-into-a-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 22:15:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/03/life-as-a-developer-advocate-nine-months-into-a-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>Back in March 2020 the western world came to somewhat of a juddering halt, thanks to COVID-19. No-one knew then what would happen, but there was the impression that whilst the next few months were a write-off for sure, maybe things would pick up again later in the year.
It’s now early December 2020, and nothing is picking up any time soon. Summer provided a respite from the high levels of infection and mortality (in the UK at least), but then numbers spiked again in many places around the world and what was punted down the river back in March is being firmly punted yet again now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Workstation - 2020</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/02/my-workstation-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 17:19:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/02/my-workstation-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is a blog even a blog nowadays if it doesn’t include a &amp;#34;Here is my home office setup&amp;#34;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to conferences all being online, and thus my talks being delivered from my study—and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=speakerselfie%20(from%3Armoff)&amp;amp;src=typed_query&amp;amp;f=live&#34;&gt;my habit of posting a #SpeakerSelfie&lt;/a&gt; each time I do a conference talk—I often get questions about my setup. Plus, I’m kinda pleased with it so I want to show it off too ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🤖Building a Telegram bot with Apache Kafka, Go, and ksqlDB</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/08/20/building-a-telegram-bot-with-apache-kafka-go-and-ksqldb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:00:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/08/20/building-a-telegram-bot-with-apache-kafka-go-and-ksqldb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of presenting at &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataengconf.com.au/&#34;&gt;DataEngBytes&lt;/a&gt; recently, and am delighted to share with you the &lt;strong&gt;🗒️ slides, 👾 code, and 🎥 recording&lt;/strong&gt; of my ✨brand new talk✨:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.dev/carpark-telegram-bot&#34;&gt;🤖Building a Telegram bot with Apache Kafka, Go, and ksqlDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Tech Conferences Dead?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/03/13/are-tech-conferences-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 22:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/03/13/are-tech-conferences-dead/</guid>
      <description>🦠COVID-19 has well and truly hit the tech scene this week. As well as being full of &amp;#34;WFH tips&amp;#34; for all the tech workers suddenly banished from their offices, my particular Twitter bubble is full of DevRel folk musing and debating about what this interruption means to our profession. For sure, in the short term, the Spring conference season is screwed— all the conferences are cancelled (or postponed).
But what about the future?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to win [or at least not suck] at the conference abstract submission game</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/01/16/how-to-win-or-at-least-not-suck-at-the-conference-abstract-submission-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 13:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/01/16/how-to-win-or-at-least-not-suck-at-the-conference-abstract-submission-game/</guid>
      <description>Just over a year ago, I put together the crudely-titled &amp;#34;Quick Thoughts on Not Writing a Crap Abstract&amp;#34; after reviewing a few dozen conference abstracts. This time around I’ve had the honour of being on a conference programme committee and with it the pleasure of reading 250+ abstracts—from which I have some more snarky words of wisdom to impart on the matter.
Remind me…how does this conference game work? Before we really get into it, let’s recap how this whole game works, because plenty of people are new to conference speaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying sane on the road as a Developer Advocate</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/19/staying-sane-on-the-road-as-a-developer-advocate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 23:38:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/19/staying-sane-on-the-road-as-a-developer-advocate/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a full-time Developer Advocate for nearly 1.5 years now, and have learnt lots along the way. The stuff I’ve learnt about being an advocate I’ve written about elsewhere (here/here/here); today I want to write about something that’s just as important: staying sane and looking after yourself whilst on the road. This is also tangentially related to another of my favourite posts that I’ve written: Travelling for Work, with Kids at Home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I&#39;ll be on the road for the remainder of 2019</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 17:36:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a relaxing couple of weeks off work over the summer, and came back today to realise that I’ve got a fair bit of conference and meetup travel to wrap my head around for the next few months :)
If you’re interested in where I’ll be and want to come and say hi, hear about Kafka—or just grab a coffee or beer, herewith my itinerary as it currently stands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts on Not Making a Crap Slide Deck</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/03/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-making-a-crap-slide-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 10:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/03/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-making-a-crap-slide-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is the companion to an earlier one that I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/&#34;&gt;conference abstracts&lt;/a&gt;. In the same way that the last one was inspired by reviewing a ton of abstracts and noticing a recurring pattern in my suggestions, so this one comes from reviewing a bunch of slide decks for a forthcoming conference. They all look like good talks, but in several cases &lt;em&gt;these great talks are fighting to get out from underneath the deadening weight of slides&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herewith follows my highly-opinionated, fairly-subjective, and extremely-terse advice and general suggestions for slide decks. You can also find relating ramblings in &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2019/03/01/preparing-a-new-talk/&#34;&gt;this recent post&lt;/a&gt; too. My friend and colleague Vik Gamov also wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamov.io/posts/2019/03/15/quick-tips-on-designing-your-next-presentation.html&#34;&gt;a good post&lt;/a&gt; on this same topic, and linked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://player.oreilly.com/videos/9781491954980&#34;&gt;a good video&lt;/a&gt; that I’d recommend you watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing a New Talk</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/03/01/preparing-a-new-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 11:00:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/03/01/preparing-a-new-talk/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written quite a few talks over the years, but usually as a side-line to my day job. In my role as a Developer Advocate, talks are part of What I Do, and so I can dedicate more time to it. A lot of the talks I’ve done previously have evolved through numerous iterations, and with a new talk to deliver for the &amp;#34;Spring Season&amp;#34; of conferences, I thought it would be interesting to track what it took from concept to actual delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling for Work, with Kids at Home</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/02/09/travelling-for-work-with-kids-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 14:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/02/09/travelling-for-work-with-kids-at-home/</guid>
      <description>I began travelling for my job when my first child was three months old. But don’t mistake correlation for causation…it wasn’t the broken nights&amp;#39; sleep that forced me onto the road, but an excellent job opportunity that seemed worth the risk. Nearly eight years later and I’m in a different job but still with a bunch of travel involved. How much I travel has varied. It’s tended to average around 30%, but has peaked at way more than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts on Not Writing a Crap Abstract</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 22:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/</guid>
      <description>I’ve reviewed a bunch of abstracts in the last couple of days, here are some common suggestions I made:
No need to include your company name in the abstract text. Chances are I’ve not heard of your company, and even if I have, what does it add to my comprehension of your abstract and what you’re going to talk about? Possible exception would be the &amp;#34;hot&amp;#34; tech companies where people will see a talk just because it’s Netflix etc</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
