<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ingest on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/tag/ingest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ingest on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:45:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/tag/ingest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with Elasticsearch, Kibana, and Timelion</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/13/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-timelion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/13/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-timelion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2016/05/12/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-influxdb-and-grafana/&#34;&gt;Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with InfluxDB and Grafana&lt;/a&gt;, in which InfluxDB provided the data store for the ingest rate data, and Grafana the frontend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/warkolm/&#34;&gt;Mark Walkom&lt;/a&gt; reminded me on twitter that the next release of Logstash will add more functionality in this area - and that it&amp;rsquo;ll integrate back into the Elastic stack:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rmoff&#34;&gt;@rmoff&lt;/a&gt; nice, LS 5.0 will have APIs exposing metrics too. they’ll be integrated back into Marvel/Monitoring! :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Logstash Ingest Rates with InfluxDB and Grafana</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/12/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-influxdb-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 20:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/12/monitoring-logstash-ingest-rates-with-influxdb-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to easily monitor the rate at which Logstash is ingesting data, as well as in future articles the rate at which Elasticsearch is indexing it. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice little touch to add to any project involving Logstash, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Logstash is powerful tool for data ingest, processing, and distribution. It originated as simply the pipe to slurp at log files and put them into Elasticsearch, but has evolved into a whole bunch more. With connectors to JDBC and Kafka, as well as many other &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/current/input-plugins.html&#34;&gt;input&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/current/output-plugins.html&#34;&gt;output&lt;/a&gt; options (not to mention the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/current/filter-plugins.html&#34;&gt;filtering&lt;/a&gt; possibilities), it really is a great bit of software to use. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it over the years with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rittmanmead.com/2014/10/monitoring-obiee-with-elasticsearch-logstash-and-kibana/&#34;&gt;OBIEE&lt;/a&gt;, as well as more recently to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elastic.co/blog/visualising-oracle-performance-data-with-the-elastic-stack&#34;&gt;pull data from Oracle&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2016/03/24/my-latest-irc-client-kibana/&#34;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;. Another great set of tools is &lt;a href=&#34;http://influxdb.com&#34;&gt;InfluxDB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://grafana.org&#34;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt;, which for me really round off the standalone Elastic platform (previously known as ELK - Elasticsearch, Logstash, and Kibana). What InfluxDB and Grafana give is a powerful dedicated time series database and flexible time series-based dashboarding tool respectively. A topic for another day is the Elasticsearch vs InfluxDB overlap, and Kibana vs Grafana - but for now, just take it as read that it&amp;rsquo;s horses for course, right tool for the right job, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
