<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>support on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in support on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does this summarise your system development &amp;amp; support ethos?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/27/does-this-summarise-your-system-development-amp-support-ethos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/27/does-this-summarise-your-system-development-amp-support-ethos/</guid>
      <description>I heard this on Thinking Allowed and thought how applicable it was to the attitudes that you can sometimes encounter in both systems development, and the support of production systems:
 “Each uneventful day that passes reinforces a steadily growing false sense of confidence that everything is all right – that I, we, my group must be OK because the way we did things today resulted in no adverse consequences.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When is a bug not a bug? When it&#39;s a &#34;design decision&#34;</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/18/when-is-a-bug-not-a-bug-when-its-a-design-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/18/when-is-a-bug-not-a-bug-when-its-a-design-decision/</guid>
      <description>Last month I wrote about a problem that Informatica as part of OBIA was causing us, wherein an expired database account would bring Oracle down by virtue of multiple connections from Informatica.
I raised an SR with Oracle (under OBIA support), who after some back-and-forth with Informatica, were told:
 This is not a bug. That the two error messages coming back from Oracle are handled differently is the result of a design decision and as such not a product fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better safe than sorry...sanitising DB input</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/22/better-safe-than-sorry...sanitising-db-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/22/better-safe-than-sorry...sanitising-db-input/</guid>
      <description>As Twitter learnt yesterday, you should always sanitise user input. I was amused to see My Oracle Support doing so&amp;hellip;.recursively :)
The apostrophe in &amp;ldquo;doesn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo; got escaped once, and then again, and then again, and then again, and then again &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s been at the cookie jar? EBS-BI authentication and Load Balancers</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/whos-been-at-the-cookie-jar-ebs-bi-authentication-and-load-balancers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/whos-been-at-the-cookie-jar-ebs-bi-authentication-and-load-balancers/</guid>
      <description>We hit a very interesting problem in our Production environment recently. We&amp;rsquo;d made no changes for a long time to the configuration, but all of a sudden users were on the phone complaining. They could login to BI from EBS but after logging in the next link they clicked took them to the OBIEE &amp;ldquo;You are not logged in&amp;rdquo; screen.
Our users login to EBS R12 and then using EBS authentication log in to OBIEE (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify your OBIEE users by setting Client ID in Oracle connection</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/26/identify-your-obiee-users-by-setting-client-id-in-oracle-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/26/identify-your-obiee-users-by-setting-client-id-in-oracle-connection/</guid>
      <description>You get a call from your friendly DBA. He says the production database is up the spout, and it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;that bee eye thingumy causing it&amp;rdquo;. What do you do now? All you&amp;rsquo;ve got to go on is a program name in the Oracle session tables of &amp;ldquo;nqsserver@MYSERVER (TNS V1-V3)&amp;rdquo; and the SQL the DBA sent you that if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky will look as presentable as this: The username against the SQL is the generic User ID that you had created for connections to the database from OBIEE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#Fail: My Oracle Support</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/11/#fail-my-oracle-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/11/#fail-my-oracle-support/</guid>
      <description>Metalink was retired this weekend and made way for the new My Oracle Support system. It didn&amp;rsquo;t go as smoothly as it could have done.
This post is going to be a bit of a rambling rant.
Ultimately people, including me, don&amp;rsquo;t like their cheese being moved (not unless there&amp;rsquo;s a really runny piece of Camembert at the end of it). That makes it a bit more difficult to discuss because some of people&amp;rsquo;s complaints will just be geeks being stubborn (and boy, can geeks be stubborn).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE error/message code reference</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/24/obiee-error/message-code-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/24/obiee-error/message-code-reference/</guid>
      <description>For some reason Oracle haven&amp;rsquo;t put out a 10.x version of the error &amp;amp; message codes reference guide for OBIEE, but the previous version for Siebel Analytics is still useful:
 PDF version: http://download.oracle.com/otndocs/products/bi/bi-ee/docs/784/AnyMsg.pdf HTML version: http://download.oracle.com/docs/cd/E12103_01/books/AnyMsg/AnyMsg_Messages.html#wp1007961  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you mean (pt II)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/20/do-you-mean-pt-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/20/do-you-mean-pt-ii/</guid>
      <description>A follow up to my previous post about Metalink&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Do you mean&amp;rdquo; feature, this one made me laugh: I shall miss this kind of thing when Metalink3 merges into My Oracle Support&amp;hellip;.
Meep meep!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metalink 3 - Do You Mean ... ?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/24/metalink-3-do-you-mean-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/24/metalink-3-do-you-mean-.../</guid>
      <description>One of my little gripes with Metalink is its purporting to be helpful when it&amp;rsquo;s blatantly not. Here&amp;rsquo;s one: Now which is more likely, on Metalink 3; that I&amp;rsquo;m searching for sawserver (integral component to OBIEE), or sqlserver?!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metalink Metalink Metalink</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/24/metalink-metalink-metalink/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/24/metalink-metalink-metalink/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m learning about a lot of the Oracle BI stack through reading manuals and trial-and-error.
One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve realised is that Metalink holds a whole heap of useful information.
For example, simply searching on &amp;ldquo;publisher cluster&amp;rdquo; throws up these two very pertinent docs:
 OBIEE Clustered Installation with BI Publisher (Doc ID 744515.1) BI Publisher does not accept cluster jdbc connection strings (Doc ID 559795.1)  The first one is a publically available PDF, the second one is the answer to the problem I spent more time than I needed to scratching my head over yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
