<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 12:14:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Sausage Factory: How we Built the Program for Current 2022</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/inside-the-sausage-factory-how-we-built-the-program-for-current-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 12:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/inside-the-sausage-factory-how-we-built-the-program-for-current-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been to a conference, particularly as a speaker whose submitted a paper that may or may not have been accepted, you might wonder quite how conferences choose the talks that get accepted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of chairing the program committee for Current and Kafka Summit this year and curating the final program for both. Here’s a glimpse behind the curtains of how we built the program for Current 2022. It was originally posted as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rmoff/status/1549410161688813569&#34;&gt;thread on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>⚡️ Writing an abstract for a lightning talk ⚡️</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/%EF%B8%8F-writing-an-abstract-for-a-lightning-talk-%EF%B8%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/08/31/%EF%B8%8F-writing-an-abstract-for-a-lightning-talk-%EF%B8%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rmoff/status/1544257707049467905&#34;&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are generally 5-10 minutes. As the name implies - they are quick!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good lightning talk is not just your breakout talk condensed into a shorter time frame. You can’t simply deliver the same material faster, or the same material at a higher level, or the same material with a few bits left out&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Good Tech Conference Abstract - Learn from the Mistakes of Others</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/07/20/how-to-write-a-good-tech-conference-abstract-learn-from-the-mistakes-of-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 08:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/07/20/how-to-write-a-good-tech-conference-abstract-learn-from-the-mistakes-of-others/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building the program for any conference is not an easy task. There will always be a speaker disappointed that their talk didn’t get in—or perhaps an audience who are disappointed that a particular talk &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; get in. As the chair of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.confluent.io/en-gb/blog/introducing-current-2022-program-committee/&#34;&gt;program committee&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.currentevent.io/&#34;&gt;Current 22&lt;/a&gt; one of the things that I’ve found really useful in building out the program this time round are the comments that the program committee left against submissions as they reviewed them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were some common patterns I saw, and I thought it would be useful to share these here. Perhaps you’re an aspiring conference speaker looking to understand what mistakes to avoid. Maybe you’re an existing speaker whose abstracts don’t get accepted as often as you’d like. Or perhaps you’re just curious as to what goes on behind the curtains :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Tech Conferences Dead?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/03/13/are-tech-conferences-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 22:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/03/13/are-tech-conferences-dead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🦠COVID-19 has well and truly hit the tech scene this week. As well as being full of &amp;#34;WFH tips&amp;#34; for all the tech workers suddenly banished from their offices, my particular Twitter bubble is full of DevRel folk musing and debating about what this interruption means to our profession. For sure, in the short term, the Spring conference season is screwed— &lt;a href=&#34;https://airtable.com/shrETNURgXNrGWbd8/tblc49hMMykARebo8?blocks=hide&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the conferences&lt;/a&gt; are cancelled (or postponed).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what about the future? No-one would ever &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to take such a forced hiatus but what an excellent opportunity it is to take a step back and consider why we’re doing what we’re doing - and if we should go back to business as usual once things calm down.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to win [or at least not suck] at the conference abstract submission game</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/01/16/how-to-win-or-at-least-not-suck-at-the-conference-abstract-submission-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 13:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/01/16/how-to-win-or-at-least-not-suck-at-the-conference-abstract-submission-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just over a year ago, I put together the crudely-titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Quick Thoughts on Not Writing a Crap Abstract&amp;#34;&lt;/a&gt; after reviewing a few dozen conference abstracts. This time around I’ve had the honour of being on a conference programme committee and with it the pleasure of reading 250+ abstracts—from which I have some more snarky words of wisdom to impart on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;_remind_mehow_does_this_conference_game_work&#34;&gt;Remind me…how does this conference game work?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we really get into it, let’s recap how this whole game works, because plenty of people are new to conference speaking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where I&#39;ll be on the road for the remainder of 2019</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 17:36:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a relaxing couple of weeks off work over the summer, and came back today to realise that I’ve got a fair bit of conference and meetup travel to wrap my head around for the next few months :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in where I’ll be and want to come and say hi, hear about Kafka—or just grab a coffee or beer, herewith my itinerary as it currently stands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts on Not Making a Crap Slide Deck</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/03/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-making-a-crap-slide-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 10:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/03/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-making-a-crap-slide-deck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is the companion to an earlier one that I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/&#34;&gt;conference abstracts&lt;/a&gt;. In the same way that the last one was inspired by reviewing a ton of abstracts and noticing a recurring pattern in my suggestions, so this one comes from reviewing a bunch of slide decks for a forthcoming conference. They all look like good talks, but in several cases &lt;em&gt;these great talks are fighting to get out from underneath the deadening weight of slides&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Herewith follows my highly-opinionated, fairly-subjective, and extremely-terse advice and general suggestions for slide decks. You can also find relating ramblings in &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2019/03/01/preparing-a-new-talk/&#34;&gt;this recent post&lt;/a&gt; too. My friend and colleague Vik Gamov also wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamov.io/posts/2019/03/15/quick-tips-on-designing-your-next-presentation.html&#34;&gt;a good post&lt;/a&gt; on this same topic, and linked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://player.oreilly.com/videos/9781491954980&#34;&gt;a good video&lt;/a&gt; that I’d recommend you watch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Thoughts on Not Writing a Crap Abstract</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 22:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/19/quick-thoughts-on-not-writing-a-crap-abstract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve reviewed a bunch of abstracts in the last couple of days, here are some common suggestions I made:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No need to include your company name in the abstract text. Chances are I’ve not heard of your company, and even if I have, what does it add to my comprehension of your abstract and what you’re going to talk about? Possible exception would be the &amp;#34;hot&amp;#34; tech companies where people will see a talk just because it’s Netflix etc&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; don’t want just to read your project documentation/summary. It makes me worry your talk will be death by PowerPoint of the minutiae of something that’s only relevant in your company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following on from above, I want to see that there’s going to be things you’ll share &lt;em&gt;that are useful for other people in a similar situation&lt;/em&gt;. Something that’s specific to your project, your company, doesn’t translate to mass-usefulness. Something that other people will hit, whether it’s technical or org-cultural, now &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; is interesting and is going to be useful&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If my eyes start to glaze over reading the abstract intro, already I’m assuming that your talk will make me bored too. Read it back out loud to yourself…make sure each word justifies its place in the text. Boilerplate filler and waffle should be left on the cutting room floor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You need to strike a balance between giving enough detail about the contents of your talk that I am convinced you have interesting things to share, but without listing every nut and bolt of detail. Too much detail and it just becomes a laundry list. You need to whet people’s appetite for the actual meal, not put them off their food.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For heaven’s sake, proof read! If you can’t be arsed to use a spell checker, then I definitely wouldn’t trust you to prepare a talk of any quality. I’ve recently started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.grammarly.com/&#34;&gt;Grammarly&lt;/a&gt; and it’s &lt;em&gt;excellent&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conferences &amp; Meetups at which I&#39;ll be speaking - 2017</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2017/09/11/conferences-meetups-at-which-ill-be-speaking-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2017/09/11/conferences-meetups-at-which-ill-be-speaking-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be speaking at several conferences and meetups over the next few months. Unsurprisingly, the topic will be Apache Kafka!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re at any of these, please do come and say hi :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;apache-kafka-meetup---london&#34;&gt;Apache Kafka Meetup - London&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My first time talking at the London Apache Kafka Meetup - always a sold-out crowd, this will be fun!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;September 20th, 19:00 : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Apache-Kafka-London/events/242981989/&#34;&gt;Look Ma, no Code! Building Streaming Data Pipelines with Apache Kafka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Slides are &lt;a href=&#34;https://talks.rmoff.net/kafka-summit-london-2018-look-ma-no-code-building-streaming-data-pipelines-with-apache-kafka-sd/&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;oracle-openworld---san-francisco&#34;&gt;Oracle OpenWorld - San Francisco&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This will be my second time at OOW - I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rittmanmead.com/blog/2014/10/first-timer-tips-for-oracle-open-world/&#34;&gt;wrote up my previous trip here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collection of Articles on How to Write a Good Conference Abstract</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/05/collection-of-articles-on-how-to-write-a-good-conference-abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/05/collection-of-articles-on-how-to-write-a-good-conference-abstract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a collection of useful articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years that give good advice on writing a good abstract, mistakes to avoid, etc:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dataeducation.com/capturing-attention-writing-great-session-descriptions/&#34;&gt;Adam Machanic - Capturing Attention: Writing Great Session Descriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.pythian.com/concrete-advice-for-abstract-writers/&#34;&gt;Gwen Shapira - Concrete Advice for Abstract Writers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dbakevlar.com/2013/10/abstracts-reviews-and-conferences-oh-my/&#34;&gt;Kellyn Pot’Vin-Gorman - Abstracts, Reviews and Conferences, Oh My!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/article/conference-proposals-that-dont-suck&#34;&gt;Russ Unger - Conference Proposals that Don’t Suck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mwidlake.wordpress.com/2015/04/17/tips-on-submitting-an-abstract-to-conference/&#34;&gt;Martin Widlake - Tips on Submitting an Abstract to Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bridgetkromhout.com/blog/give-actionable-takeaways/&#34;&gt;Bridget Kromhout - give actionable takeaways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(post photo courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@calum_mac&#34;&gt;Calum MacAulay&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com&#34;&gt;https://unsplash.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
