<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:27:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo not detecting changed pages on Mac</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2023/11/16/hugo-not-detecting-changed-pages-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2023/11/16/hugo-not-detecting-changed-pages-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used Hugo for my blog for several years now, and it&amp;rsquo;s great. One of the things I love about it is the fast build time coupled with it&amp;rsquo;s live-reload feature. Using this I can edit my source (Markdown or Asciidoc) in one window, hit save, and see the preview update in my browser window next to it pretty much instantaneously. For copy-editing, experimenting with images, etc this is really helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub Actions to build automagic Hugo previews of draft articles</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/06/using-github-actions-to-build-automagic-hugo-previews-of-draft-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2022/04/06/using-github-actions-to-build-automagic-hugo-previews-of-draft-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is written in Asciidoc, built using Hugo, and hosted on GitHub Pages. I recently wanted to share the draft of a post I was writing with someone and ended up exporting a local preview to a PDF - not a great workflow! This blog post shows you how to create an automagic hosted preview of any draft content on Hugo using GitHub Actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is useful for previewing and sharing one’s own content, but also for making good use of GitHub as a collaborative platform - if someone &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rmoff/rmoff-blog/pull/4#pullrequestreview-933907051&#34;&gt;reviews and amends your PR&lt;/a&gt; the post gets updated in the preview too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling Hugo Builds on GitHub pages with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/20/scheduling-hugo-builds-on-github-pages-with-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 23:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/12/20/scheduling-hugo-builds-on-github-pages-with-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve used various blogging platforms; after a brief dalliance with Blogger I started for real with the near-inevitable Wordpress.com. From there I decided it would be fun to self-host using Ghost, and then almost &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;exactly two years ago to the day&lt;/a&gt; decided it definitely was not fun to spend time patching and upgrading my blog platform instead of writing blog articles, so headed over to my current platform of choice: Hugo hosted on GitHub pages. This has worked extremely well for me during that time, doing everything I want from it until recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including content from external links with Asciidoc in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/09/18/including-content-from-external-links-with-asciidoc-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 09:00:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/09/18/including-content-from-external-links-with-asciidoc-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I use Hugo for my blog, hosted on GitHub pages. One of the reasons I’m really happy with it is that I can use Asciidoc to author my posts. I was writing a blog recently in which I wanted to include some code that’s hosted on GitHub. I could have copied &amp;amp; pasted it into the blog but that would be lame!
With Asciidoc you can use the include:: directive to include both local files:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Ghost to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2018/12/17/moving-from-ghost-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Why? I’ve been blogging for quite a few years now, starting on Blogger, soon onto WordPress, and then to Ghost a couple of years ago. Blogger was fairly lame, WP yucky, but I really do like Ghost. It’s simple and powerful and was perfect for my needs. My needs being, an outlet for technical content that respected formatting, worked with a markup language (Markdown), and didn’t f**k things up in the way that WP often would in its WYSIWYG handling of content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
