<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bug on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/bug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bug on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/bug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Security issue on OBIEE 10.1.3.4.1, 11.1.1.3</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/04/security-issue-on-obiee-10.1.3.4.1-11.1.1.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/04/security-issue-on-obiee-10.1.3.4.1-11.1.1.3/</guid>
      <description>July&amp;rsquo;s Critical Patch Update from Oracle includes CVE-2011-2241, which affects OBIEE versions 10.1.3.4.1 and 11.1.1.3. No details of the exploit other than it &amp;ldquo;allows remote attackers to affect availability via unknown vectors related to Analytics Server.&amp;rdquo;
It is categorised with a CVSS score of 5 (on a scale of 10), with no impact on Authentication, Confidentiality, or Integrity, and &amp;ldquo;Partial+&amp;rdquo; impact on Availability. So to a security-unqualified layman (me), it sounds like someone could remotely crash your NQSServer process, but not do any more damage than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE Systems Management - dodgy counter behaviour</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/08/obiee-systems-management-dodgy-counter-behaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/08/obiee-systems-management-dodgy-counter-behaviour/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of exploring of OBIEE Systems Management data, covered in a mini-series of blog posts, Collecting OBIEE systems management data.
There are a vast number of counters exposed, ranging from the very interesting (Active Sessions, Cache Hits, etc) to the less so (Total Query Piggybacks, although for some seriously hardcore performance tuning even this may be of interest).
This short blog post is about a couple of counters which I&amp;rsquo;ve been monitoring but which looks to not be entirely reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Materialised Views - PCT Partition Truncation</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/01/08/materialised-views-pct-partition-truncation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/01/08/materialised-views-pct-partition-truncation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some work recently that involved the use of Materialised Views on Oracle 11g (11.1.0.7), particularly around PCT refresh. There are some things that are not clear from the documentation, or are actually bugs so far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned, and I&amp;rsquo;ve detailed these below.
In this example I was working on part of a DWH with c.2 millions rows aggregated up daily. One of the things that I spent a long time trying to get to work was Partition Truncation when using PCT refresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misbehaving Informatica kills Oracle</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/02/misbehaving-informatica-kills-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/02/misbehaving-informatica-kills-oracle/</guid>
      <description>This problem, which in essence is bad behaviour from Informatica bringing down Oracle, is a good illustration of unintended consequences of an apparently innocuous security setting. Per our company&amp;rsquo;s security standards, database passwords expire every 90 days. When this happens users are prompted to change their password before they can continue logging into Oracle. This applies to application user IDs too. It appears that Informatica 8.6.1 HF6 (part of OBIA 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Patch Update - OBIEE vuln CVE-2009-1990</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/21/critical-patch-update-obiee-vuln-cve-2009-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/21/critical-patch-update-obiee-vuln-cve-2009-1990/</guid>
      <description>October&amp;rsquo;s Oracle Critical Patch Update Advisory has been released. There are two vulnerabilities (CVE-2009-1999, CVE-2009-1990) listed under Oracle Application Server for &amp;ldquo;Component&amp;rdquo; Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition and one (CVE-2009-3407) for &amp;ldquo;component&amp;rdquo; Portal.
CVE-2009-1999 is OBIEE and &amp;ldquo;Fixed in all supported versions. No patch provided in this Critical Patch Update.&amp;rdquo;. CVE-2009-3407 looks like only OAS (not OBIEE), up to versions 10.1.2.3 and 10.1.4.2. CVE-2009-1990 is OBIEE and is the main vuln of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads up - Critical Patch Update affecting OBIEE</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/16/heads-up-critical-patch-update-affecting-obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/16/heads-up-critical-patch-update-affecting-obiee/</guid>
      <description>The Critical Patch Update Pre-Release Announcement for October has been published. The pre-release is advance notice of the affected software prior to release of the quarterly Critical Patch Update. It is published on the Thursday prior to the patch releases (which was postponed by a week because of OOW).
It looks like if you&amp;rsquo;re running OBIEE 10.1.3.4.0 or 10.1.3.4.1 through OAS 10.1.2.3.0/10.1.3.4.0/10.1.3.5.0 then you should check back next Tuesday 20th for details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIA upgrade 7.9.5 to 7.9.6 - first thoughts</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/13/obia-upgrade-7.9.5-to-7.9.6-first-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/13/obia-upgrade-7.9.5-to-7.9.6-first-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re upgrading from OBIA 7.9.5 (Financials - GL) to OBIA 7.9.6. Our reasons are for support (7.9.5 does not support Oracle 11g) and minor functionality additions.
Our architecture is: HP-UX 64 bit Itanium (11.31), Oracle 11g (11.1.0.7), separate ETL server, 4x OBIEE servers (2x BI, 2xPS). We have no customisations in the ETL except something for budgets, which is superseded in 7.9.6.
This post is a semi-formed articulation of my frustrations encountered during an initial run through of the upgrade in a sandbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sawserver charts crash</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/sawserver-charts-crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/sawserver-charts-crash/</guid>
      <description>By a strange co-incidence after following this thread on OTN forums about a BI crash and struggling to understand the actual problem, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered it myself!
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a test install of OBIEE running on my Windows XP laptop, and whilst building a report in Answers got this:
](http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_RCx_EVJpczQ/SmiDrEorbbI/AAAAAAAAGcg/OPGwTLXXg8k/s1600/crash1.png)[![](/images/rnm1978/crash2.png) was:
szAppName : sawserver.exe szAppVer : 10.1.3.4 szModName : kernel32.dll szModVer : 5.1.2600.3119 offset : 000097a3
Going to the sawserver log at c:\OracleBIData\web\log\sawlog0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
