<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GCP on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/gcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GCP on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 14:45:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running Dockerised Kafka Connect worker on GCP</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/11/12/running-dockerised-kafka-connect-worker-on-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/11/12/running-dockerised-kafka-connect-worker-on-gcp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://talks.rmoff.net/&#34;&gt;talk and write about Kafka and Confluent Platform&lt;/a&gt; a lot, and more and more of the demos that I’m building are around &lt;a href=&#34;https://confluent.cloud&#34;&gt;Confluent Cloud&lt;/a&gt;. This means that I don’t have to run or manage my own Kafka brokers, Zookeeper, Schema Registry, KSQL servers, etc which makes things a ton easier. Whilst there are managed connectors on Confluent Cloud (S3 etc), I need to run my own Kafka Connect worker for those connectors not yet provided. An example is the MQTT source connector that I use in &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmoff.dev/kssf19-ksql-video&#34;&gt;this demo&lt;/a&gt;. Up until now I’d either run this worker locally, or manually build a cloud VM. Locally is fine, as it’s all Docker, easily spun up in a single &lt;code&gt;docker-compose up -d&lt;/code&gt; command. I wanted something that would keep running whilst my laptop was off, but that was as close to my local build as possible—enter GCP and its functionality to run a container on a VM automagically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/confluentinc/demo-scene/blob/master/mqtt-tracker/launch-worker-container_gcloud.sh&#34;&gt;the full script here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The rest of this article just walks through the how and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
