<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>obiee on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/obiee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in obiee on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 20:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/obiee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lifting the Lid on OBIEE 12c Web Services - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/28/lifting-the-lid-on-obiee-12c-web-services-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/28/lifting-the-lid-on-obiee-12c-web-services-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In OBIEE 12c data-model-cmd is a wrapper for some java code which ultimately calls an internal RESTful web service in OBIEE 12c, bi-lcm. We saw in the previous post how these internal web services can be opened up slightly, and we&amp;rsquo;re going to do the same again here. Which means, time for the same caveat:
 None of these Web Services are documented, and they should therefore be assumed to be completely unsupported by Oracle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Naming of OBIEE 12c Service Instance Exports</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/27/dynamic-naming-of-obiee-12c-service-instance-exports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 09:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/27/dynamic-naming-of-obiee-12c-service-instance-exports/</guid>
      <description>exportServiceInstance will export the RPD, Presentation Catalog, and Security model (application roles &amp;amp; policies etc &amp;ndash; but not WLS LDAP) into a single .bar file, from which they can be imported to another environment, or restored to the same one at a later date (e.g. for backup/restore).
To run exportServiceInstance you need to launch WLST first. The following demonstrates how to call it, and embeds the current timestamp &amp;amp; machine details in the backup (useful info, and also makes the backup name unique each time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE 12c - &#34;Add Data Source&#34; in Answers</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/27/obiee-12c-add-data-source-in-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 08:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/27/obiee-12c-add-data-source-in-answers/</guid>
      <description>So this had me scratching my head for a good hour today. Comparing SampleApp v511 against a vanilla OBIEE 12c install I&amp;rsquo;d done, one had &amp;ldquo;Add Data Source&amp;rdquo; as an option in Answers, the other didn&amp;rsquo;t. The strange thing was that the option wasn&amp;rsquo;t there in SampleApp &amp;ndash; and usually that has all the bells and whistles enabled.
After checking and re-checking the Manage Privileges option, and even the Application Policy grants, and the manual, I hit MoS - and turned up Doc ID 2093886.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifting the Lid on OBIEE 12c Web Services - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/24/lifting-the-lid-on-obiee-12c-web-services-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/24/lifting-the-lid-on-obiee-12c-web-services-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Architecturally, OBIEE 12c is - on the surface - pretty similar to OBIEE 11g. Sure, we&amp;rsquo;ve lost OPMN in favour of Node Manager, but all the old favourites are there - WebLogic Servers, BI Server (nqsserver / OBIS), Presentation Services (sawserver / OBIPS), and so on.
But, scratch beneath the surface, or have a gander at slide decks such as this one from BIWA this year, and you realise that change is afoot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE 12c hangs at startup - Starting AdminServer ...</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/20/obiee-12c-hangs-at-startup-starting-adminserver-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 14:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/20/obiee-12c-hangs-at-startup-starting-adminserver-.../</guid>
      <description>Running the OBIEE 12c startup on Windows:
C:\app\oracle\fmw\user_projects\domains\bi\bitools\bin\start.cmd  Just hangs at:
Starting AdminServer ...  No CPU being consumed, very odd. But then &amp;hellip; looking at DOMAIN_HOME\servers\AdminServer\logs\AdminServer.out shows the last log entry was:
Enter username to boot WebLogic server:  And that&amp;rsquo;s bad news, cos that&amp;rsquo;s an interactive prompt, but not echo&amp;rsquo;d to the console output of the startup command, and there&amp;rsquo;s no way to interact with it.
The start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oracle.bi.bar.exceptions.UnSupportedBarException: The Bar file provided as input is not supported in this BI Platfrom release.</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/19/oracle.bi.bar.exceptions.unsupportedbarexception-the-bar-file-provided-as-input-is-not-supported-in-this-bi-platfrom-release./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 10:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/19/oracle.bi.bar.exceptions.unsupportedbarexception-the-bar-file-provided-as-input-is-not-supported-in-this-bi-platfrom-release./</guid>
      <description>Another quick note on OBIEE 12c, this time on the importServiceInstance command. If you run it with a BAR file that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, it&amp;rsquo;ll fail (obviously), but the error at the end of the stack trace is slightly confusing:
oracle.bi.bar.exceptions.UnSupportedBarException: The Bar file provided as input is not supported in this BI Platfrom release.  Scrolling back up the stack trace does show the error message:
SEVERE: Failed in reading bar file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE Baseline Validation Tool - Parameter &#39;directory&#39; is not a directory</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/18/obiee-baseline-validation-tool-parameter-directory-is-not-a-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/05/18/obiee-baseline-validation-tool-parameter-directory-is-not-a-directory/</guid>
      <description>Interesting quirk in running Baseline Validation Tool for OBIEE here. If you invoke obibvt from the bin folder, it errors with Parameter &amp;lsquo;directory&amp;rsquo; is not a directory
PS C:\OracleBI-BVT&amp;gt; cd bin PS C:\OracleBI-BVT\bin&amp;gt; .\obibvt -config C:\OracleBI-BVT\bin\bvt-config.xml -deployment current INFO: Result folder: Results\current Throwable: Parameter &#39;directory&#39; is not a directory Thread[main,5,main] SEVERE: Unhandled Exception SEVERE: java.lang.IllegalArgumentException: Parameter &#39;directory&#39; is not a directory at org.apache.commons.io.FileUtils.validateListFilesParameters(FileUtils.java:545) at org.apache.commons.io.FileUtils.listFiles(FileUtils.java:521) at org.apache.commons.io.FileUtils.listFiles(FileUtils.java:691) at com.oracle.biee.bvt.UpgradeTool.loadPlugins(UpgradeTool.java:537) at com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE security patches, and FINAL 11.1.1.7 patchset release</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/04/18/obiee-security-patches-and-final-11.1.1.7-patchset-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/04/18/obiee-security-patches-and-final-11.1.1.7-patchset-release/</guid>
      <description>Two vulns for OBIEE in the latest critical patch update (CPU): http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/security-advisory/cpuapr2016v3-2985753.html?elq_mid=45463&amp;amp;sh=91225181314122121267715271910&amp;amp;cmid=WWMK10067711MPP001C140
Patches is bundle patch .160419:
 12.2.1: https://support.oracle.com/epmos/faces/ui/patch/PatchDetail.jspx?parent=DOCUMENT&amp;amp;sourceId=2102148.1&amp;amp;patchId=22734181 11.1.1.9: https://support.oracle.com/epmos/faces/ui/patch/PatchDetail.jspx?parent=DOCUMENT&amp;amp;sourceId=2102148.1&amp;amp;patchId=22393988 11.1.1.7: https://support.oracle.com/epmos/faces/ui/patch/PatchDetail.jspx?parent=DOCUMENT&amp;amp;sourceId=2102148.1&amp;amp;patchId=22225110  Note that April 2016 is the last regular patchset for 11.1.1.7, ref: https://support.oracle.com/epmos/faces/DocumentDisplay?id=2102148.1#mozTocId410847. If you&amp;rsquo;re still on it, or earlier, time to upgrade!
 (Photo credit: https://unsplash.com/@jenlittlebirdie)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to OBIEE via JDBC - with jisql</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/03/28/connecting-to-obiee-via-jdbc-with-jisql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/03/28/connecting-to-obiee-via-jdbc-with-jisql/</guid>
      <description>OBIEE supports JDBC as a connection protocol, using the driver available on all installations of OBIEE, bijdbc.jar. This makes connecting to OBIEE from custom or third-party applications very easy. Once connected, you issue &amp;ldquo;Logical SQL&amp;rdquo; against the &amp;ldquo;tables&amp;rdquo; of the Presentation Layer. An example of logical SQL is:
SELECT&amp;#34;Time&amp;#34;.&amp;#34;T05 Per Name Year&amp;#34;saw_0FROM&amp;#34;A - Sample Sales&amp;#34;To find more Logical SQL simply inspect your nqquery.log (obis-query.log in 12c), or Usage Tracking.
You can use JDBC from the command line with jisql, which is a useful command-line JDBC client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE 11.1.1.9 installation - JPS-06514: Opening of file based keystore failed</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/03/18/obiee-11.1.1.9-installation-jps-06514-opening-of-file-based-keystore-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 18:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/03/18/obiee-11.1.1.9-installation-jps-06514-opening-of-file-based-keystore-failed/</guid>
      <description>I got this lovely failure during a fresh install of OBIEE 11.1.1.9. I emphasise that it was during the install because there&amp;rsquo;s other causes for this error on an existing system to do with corrupted credential stores etc &amp;ndash; not the case here.
The install had copied in the binaries and was in the process of building the domain. During the early stages of this where it starts configuring and restarting the AdminServer it failed, with the AdminServer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising OBIEE DMS Metrics over the years</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2016/02/26/visualising-obiee-dms-metrics-over-the-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2016/02/26/visualising-obiee-dms-metrics-over-the-years/</guid>
      <description>It struck me today when I was writing my most recent blog over at Rittman Mead that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with visualising OBIEE metrics for years now.
  Back in 2009 I wrote about using something called JManage to pull metrics out of OBIEE 10g via JMX:
  Still with OBIEE 10g in 2011, I was using rrdtool and some horrible-looking tcl hacking to get the metrics out through jmx :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/11/28/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/11/28/blogging/</guid>
      <description>I will now be blogging mostly over at the venerable blog of my employer, Rittman Mead.
You can see my first posting here: Web Services in BI Publisher 11g.
Don&amp;rsquo;t entirely exclude this rnm1978 blog from your feeds, as I may still post more esoteric and random tidbits here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrumenting OBIEE - the final chapter</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/10/10/instrumenting-obiee-the-final-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/10/10/instrumenting-obiee-the-final-chapter/</guid>
      <description>This article has been superseded by a newer version: Instrumenting OBIEE Database Connections For Improved Performance Diagnostics   (Previously on this blog: 1, 2, 3&amp;hellip;)
Summary Instrument your code. Stop guessing. Make your DBA happy. Make your life as a BI Admin easier.
The Problem OBIEE will typically connect to the database using a generic application account. (Hopefully, you&amp;rsquo;ll have isolated it to an account used only for this purpose - if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, you should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday miscellany</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/09/16/friday-miscellany/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/09/16/friday-miscellany/</guid>
      <description> If you only read one blog post this month, read James Morle&amp;rsquo;s eloquent attack on the term &amp;ldquo;Best Practice&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to be joining RittmanMead next month! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to working with some of the industry&amp;rsquo;s most respected experts.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog from Oracle - OBI Product Assurance</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/15/new-blog-from-oracle-obi-product-assurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/15/new-blog-from-oracle-obi-product-assurance/</guid>
      <description>Blogging from Oracle itself about OBIEE has always been a bit sparse, certainly in comparison to that which there is for core RDBMS.
It&amp;rsquo;s good to see a new blog emerge in the last couple of months from OBI Product Assurance, including some nice &amp;lsquo;n spicy detailed config/tuning info.
Find it here: http://blogs.oracle.com/pa/.
There&amp;rsquo;s a couple more OBI blogs from Oracle, but both are fairly stale:
 Implementing Oracle BI &amp;amp; EPM Solutions - Rob Reynolds OBIEE Ramblings Oracle BI Foundation (thanks Daan for pointing this one out)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did you hear that thunk? That was me falling off my chair in shock</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/08/did-you-hear-that-thunk-that-was-me-falling-off-my-chair-in-shock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/08/did-you-hear-that-thunk-that-was-me-falling-off-my-chair-in-shock/</guid>
      <description>OK, a bit tired on a Monday morning, and so a bit sarcastic.
I&amp;rsquo;ve not really fallen off my chair, but I am shocked. I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t think it would happen.
Oracle have finally released OBI 11g for HP-UX Itanium:
In other news, patchset 10.1.3.4.2 for OBI 10g was released today, I wonder if/when we&amp;rsquo;ll get an HP-UX Itanium version? The download page has it conspicuous by its absence even from &amp;ldquo;Coming Soon&amp;rdquo;: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you defined CLIENT_ID in OBIEE yet?</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/08/have-you-defined-client_id-in-obiee-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/08/have-you-defined-client_id-in-obiee-yet/</guid>
      <description>Have you defined CLIENT_ID in your OBIEE RPD yet? You really ought to.
As well as helping track down users of troublesome queries, it also tags dump files with the OBIEE user of an offending query should the worst occur: For details, see:
 Identify your OBIEE users by setting Client ID in Oracle connection Instrumenting OBIEE for tracing Oracle DB calls  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE 10.1.3.4.2 released</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/08/obiee-10.1.3.4.2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/08/obiee-10.1.3.4.2-released/</guid>
      <description>A new version of OBI 10g (remember that?) has just been released, the Oracle twitter machine announced: Along with presumably a bunch of bugfixes, the release notes list new functionality in catalog manager: Download 10.1.3.4.2 from here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security issue on OBIEE 10.1.3.4.1, 11.1.1.3</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/04/security-issue-on-obiee-10.1.3.4.1-11.1.1.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/04/security-issue-on-obiee-10.1.3.4.1-11.1.1.3/</guid>
      <description>July&amp;rsquo;s Critical Patch Update from Oracle includes CVE-2011-2241, which affects OBIEE versions 10.1.3.4.1 and 11.1.1.3. No details of the exploit other than it &amp;ldquo;allows remote attackers to affect availability via unknown vectors related to Analytics Server.&amp;rdquo;
It is categorised with a CVSS score of 5 (on a scale of 10), with no impact on Authentication, Confidentiality, or Integrity, and &amp;ldquo;Partial+&amp;rdquo; impact on Availability. So to a security-unqualified layman (me), it sounds like someone could remotely crash your NQSServer process, but not do any more damage than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undocumented nqcmd parameters</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/07/13/undocumented-nqcmd-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/07/13/undocumented-nqcmd-parameters/</guid>
      <description>I noticed on Nico&amp;rsquo;s wiki (which is amazing by the way, it has so much information in it) a bunch of additional parameters for nqcmd other than those which are displayed in the default helptext (nqcmd -h).
These are the additional ones: [sourcecode] -b-w&amp;lt;# wait seconds&amp;gt; -c&amp;lt;# cancel interval seconds&amp;gt; -n&amp;lt;# number of loops&amp;gt; -r&amp;lt;# number of requests per shared session&amp;gt; -t&amp;lt;# number of threads&amp;gt; -T (a flag to turn on time statistics) -SmartDiff (a flag to enable SmartDiff tags in output) -P-impersonate -runas [/sourcecode]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE performance - get your database sweating</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/05/19/obiee-performance-get-your-database-sweating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/05/19/obiee-performance-get-your-database-sweating/</guid>
      <description>Just because something produces the correct numbers on the report, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you can stop there.
How you are producing those numbers matters, and matters a lot if you have an interest in the long-term health of your system and its ability to scale.
OBIEE is the case in point here, but the principle applies to any architecture with &amp;gt;1 tiers or components.
Let me start with a rhetorical question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE Systems Management - dodgy counter behaviour</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/08/obiee-systems-management-dodgy-counter-behaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/08/obiee-systems-management-dodgy-counter-behaviour/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of exploring of OBIEE Systems Management data, covered in a mini-series of blog posts, Collecting OBIEE systems management data.
There are a vast number of counters exposed, ranging from the very interesting (Active Sessions, Cache Hits, etc) to the less so (Total Query Piggybacks, although for some seriously hardcore performance tuning even this may be of interest).
This short blog post is about a couple of counters which I&amp;rsquo;ve been monitoring but which looks to not be entirely reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing LDAP settings in an OBIEE RPD with UDML</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/02/23/changing-ldap-settings-in-an-obiee-rpd-with-udml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/02/23/changing-ldap-settings-in-an-obiee-rpd-with-udml/</guid>
      <description>A chap called Kevin posted a comment on a previous posting of mine asking
 did you ever come across anything that could be used to change the LDAP server settings from a command line (admintool.exe, UDML, or otherwise)?
 I did a quick play around with some UDML and it appears that you can.
Set up the initial LDAP server definition in the RPD First I added a dummy LDAP server to samplesales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrumenting OBIEE for tracing Oracle DB calls</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/02/02/instrumenting-obiee-for-tracing-oracle-db-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/02/02/instrumenting-obiee-for-tracing-oracle-db-calls/</guid>
      <description>Cary Millsap recently published a paper &amp;ldquo;Mastering Performance with Extended SQL Trace&amp;rdquo; describing how to use Oracle trace to assist with troubleshooting the performance of database queries. As with all of Cary Millsap&amp;rsquo;s papers it is superbly written, presenting very detailed information in a clear and understandable way. (and yes I do have a DBA crush ;-)) It discusses how you can automate the tracing of specific sessions on the database, and requiring the application to be appropriately instrumented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding OBIEE monitoring graphs into OAS</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/adding-obiee-monitoring-graphs-into-oas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/adding-obiee-monitoring-graphs-into-oas/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the third part of three detailed articles making up a mini-series about OBIEE monitoring. It demonstrates how to capture OBIEE performance information, and optionally graph it out and serve it through an auto-updating webpage.
This final article describes how to bolt on to OAS a simple web page hosting the graphs that you created in part 2, plotting data from OBIEE collected in part 1.
The webpage This is just an old-school basic HTML page, with a meta-refresh tag (which note that Chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with) and img tags:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting OBIEE performance data with gnuplot</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/charting-obiee-performance-data-with-gnuplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/charting-obiee-performance-data-with-gnuplot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the second part of three detailed articles making up a mini-series about OBIEE monitoring. It demonstrates how to capture OBIEE performance information, and optionally graph it out and serve it through an auto-updating webpage.
This article takes data that part one showed you how to collect into a tab-separated file that looks something like this:
[sourcecode] 2010-11-29-14:48:18 1 0 11 0 3 2 1 676 340 0 53 1 0 41 0 3 0 2010-11-29-14:49:18 1 0 11 0 3 2 1 676 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 3 0 2010-11-29-14:50:18 2 0 16 1 4 3 1 679 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:51:18 2 2 19 1 4 3 1 679 32 0 53 1 0 58 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:52:18 2 1 19 1 4 3 4 682 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:53:18 2 1 19 1 4 3 4 682 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:54:18 2 0 19 1 4 3 1 682 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 [/sourcecode]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting OBIEE systems management data with jmx</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/collecting-obiee-systems-management-data-with-jmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/collecting-obiee-systems-management-data-with-jmx/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the first part of three detailed articles making up a mini-series about OBIEE monitoring. It demonstrates how to capture OBIEE performance information, and optionally graph it out and serve it through an auto-updating webpage.
For some background on OBIEE&amp;rsquo;s Systems Management component, along with JMX and MBeans, see here and here. The following assumes you know your mbeans from coffee beans and jmx from a bmx.
The metric collection is built around the jmxsh tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE monitoring</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/obiee-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/obiee-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who read my blog regularly may have noticed I have a slight obsession with the OBIEE systems management capability which is exposed through JMX. Venkat has blogged this week about JMX in OBI11g, and it&amp;rsquo;s clearly a technology worth understanding properly. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been tinkering with how to make use of it for monitoring purposes, most recently using JConsole and discussed here. What follows is an extension of this idea, cobbled together with a bit of shell scripting, awk, gnuplot, and sticky backed plastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE 10g - javahost hang</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/03/obiee-10g-javahost-hang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/03/obiee-10g-javahost-hang/</guid>
      <description>Hot on the heels of one problem, another has just reared its head.
Users started reporting an error with reports that included charts: [sourcecode] Chart server does not appear to be responding in a timely fashion. It may be under heavy load or unavailable. [/sourcecode]
Set up is a OBIEE 10.1.3.4.1 two-server deployment with BI/PS/Javahost clustered and loadbalanced throughout.
Diagnostics Javahost was running, and listening, on both servers: [sourcecode] $ps -ef|grep javahost obieeadm 14076 1 0 Nov 25 ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting OBIEE - LDAP (ADSI) authentication</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/02/troubleshooting-obiee-ldap-adsi-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/02/troubleshooting-obiee-ldap-adsi-authentication/</guid>
      <description>They say about travelling that it&amp;rsquo;s the journey and not the destination, and the same is true with this problem we hit during a deployment to Production.
We were deploying a new OBIEE 10g implementation, with authentication provided by Microsoft Active Directory (AD) through the LDAP functionality in OBIEE. As a side note, it&amp;rsquo;s a rather nice way to do authentication, although maybe I&amp;rsquo;m biased coming from our previous implementation which used EBS integrated authentication and was a bugger to set up and work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Poor Man&#39;s OBIEE EM/BI Management Pack</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/11/04/a-poor-mans-obiee-em/bi-management-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/11/04/a-poor-mans-obiee-em/bi-management-pack/</guid>
      <description>Folk from Yorkshire are tight, so the stereotype goes. So here&amp;rsquo;s a cheap-ass way to monitor OBIEE 10g using nothing but the OBIEE built-in systemsmanagement component, the jmx agent, and jconsole (which is part of the standard Java distribution):
From here you can also export to CSV the various counters, and then store history, plot it out with gnuplot or Excel, etc.
If anyone&amp;rsquo;s interested let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll document a bit more about how I did this, but it&amp;rsquo;s basically building on previous work I&amp;rsquo;ve documented around jmx and OBIEE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two excellent OBI presentations from Jeff McQuigg</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/27/two-excellent-obi-presentations-from-jeff-mcquigg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/27/two-excellent-obi-presentations-from-jeff-mcquigg/</guid>
      <description>Jeff McQuigg has posted two presentations that he gave at Openworld 2010 on his website here: http://greatobi.wordpress.com/2010/10/26/oow-presos/
They&amp;rsquo;re full of real content and well worth a read. There&amp;rsquo;s excellent levels of detail and plenty to think about if you&amp;rsquo;re involved in OBI or DW development projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>awk - split a fixed width file into separate files named on content</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/19/awk-split-a-fixed-width-file-into-separate-files-named-on-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/19/awk-split-a-fixed-width-file-into-separate-files-named-on-content/</guid>
      <description>More of a unix thing than DW/BI this post, but I have a beard so am semi-qualified&amp;hellip;.
The requirement was to improve the performance of some ODI processing that as part of its work was taking one huge input file, and splitting it into chunks based on content in the file. To add some (minor) spice the file was fixed width with no deliminators, so the easy awk answers that I found on google weren&amp;rsquo;t applicable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTFM? But where TF is the FM?  &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Offline searchable OBIEE 11g documentation</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/13/rtfm-but-where-tf-is-the-fm-gtgt-offline-searchable-obiee-11g-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/13/rtfm-but-where-tf-is-the-fm-gtgt-offline-searchable-obiee-11g-documentation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a geek. I like understanding things in their absolute entirety. It frustrates me to have to make presumptions or assumptions about something. I like to get down &amp;lsquo;n dirty and find out what makes things tick.
So that necessitates reading manuals. And unfortunately, Oracle don&amp;rsquo;t make that easy all the time.
Some of the manuals are not very good, and others are difficult to find. Given the complexity of the OBIEE stack and proliferation of terminology and product names, sorting the wheat from the chaff can be a headache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring real user response times for OBIEE</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/14/measuring-real-user-response-times-for-obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/14/measuring-real-user-response-times-for-obiee/</guid>
      <description>@alexgorbachev tweeted me recently after picking up my presentation on Performance Testing and OBIEE. His question got me thinking, and as ever the answer &amp;ldquo;It Depends&amp;rdquo; is appropriate here :-)
Why is the measurement being done? Without knowing the context of the work Alex is doing, how to measure depends on whether the measurement needs to be of: -
 The actual response times that the users are getting, or The response times that the system is currently capable of delivering  This may sound like splitting hairs or beard-scratching irrelevance, but it&amp;rsquo;s not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripts to extract information from OBIEE NQQuery.log</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/11/scripts-to-extract-information-from-obiee-nqquery.log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/11/scripts-to-extract-information-from-obiee-nqquery.log/</guid>
      <description>Here are a couple of little unix scripts that I wrote whilst developing my performance testing OBIEE method.
They&amp;rsquo;re nothing particularly special, but may save you the couple of minutes it&amp;rsquo;d take to write them :)
Note that some of this data is available from Usage Tracking and where it is I&amp;rsquo;d recommend getting it from there, databases generally being easier to reliably and repeatably query than a transient log file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE 11g launch date - 7th July 2010</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/03/obiee-11g-launch-date-7th-july-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/03/obiee-11g-launch-date-7th-july-2010/</guid>
      <description>OBIEE 11g is going to be officially launched on 7th July (this year!) in London: Launch Event: Introducing Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition 11g
h/t to Twitter and blogs (including an Oracle-branded one) this morning. Good news travels fast! :-)
Looks like John Minkjan won the bet, did he know something we didn&amp;rsquo;t? ;-) (although is &amp;ldquo;Launch&amp;rdquo; the same as &amp;ldquo;GA&amp;rdquo;?)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing and OBIEE</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/24/performance-testing-and-obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/24/performance-testing-and-obiee/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my presentation &amp;ldquo;Performance Testing and OBIEE&amp;rdquo; that I gave at the RittmanMead BI Forum 2010: Performance Testing and OBIEE.pptx
It&amp;rsquo;s a Powerpoint 2007 file (pptx) for which you may need the Microsoft PowerPoint Viewer 2007. I&amp;rsquo;ve included copious notes on each slide which hopefully cover the gist of what I talked about when I was delivering it. There are also a handful of funky animations which is why I&amp;rsquo;ve left it in pptx and not exported to PDF or other format (sorry Open Office users).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RittmanMead BI Forum 2010</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/21/rittmanmead-bi-forum-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/21/rittmanmead-bi-forum-2010/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just returned from the RittmanMead 2010 BI Forum which this year was at the Seattle Hotel in Brighton Marina.

The event was limited to 50 attendees, and I think this was a good number. The event was explicitly pitched at a very technical expert level, and the audience very much represented this. Whereas at a larger conference you may find the odd manager wandering around pretending to be technical ;-) this event was most definitely not pitched at such types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating EBS-BI authentication, without BI</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/17/validating-ebs-bi-authentication-without-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/17/validating-ebs-bi-authentication-without-bi/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting EBS-BI integrated authentication can be a tiresome activity, so here&amp;rsquo;s a shortcut that might help. If you suspect the problem lies with EBS then you can leave OBIEE out of the equation.
  Login to EBS
  Use FireBug or Fiddler2 to inspect web traffic as follows:
  Click the BI link from EBS
  Should be first a request to EBS server, which returns 302 and redirects to http://&amp;lt;bi server&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/analytics/saw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first presentation - help!</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/04/21/my-first-presentation-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/04/21/my-first-presentation-help/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m doing my first ever conference presentation next month at the 2010 Rittman Mead BI Forum.
My presentation is called Performance Testing OBIEE, which is something I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time working on over the last few months. I think the challenge is going to be distilling it all into a session that&amp;rsquo;s not going to overwhelm everyone or bore them to death! Well, actually, the challenge is going to be the presenting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE 11g tidbit - XUDML support</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/18/obiee-11g-tidbit-xudml-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/18/obiee-11g-tidbit-xudml-support/</guid>
      <description>Spotted this when trawling through My Oracle Support. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common knowledge anyway amongst people already familiar with hacking around with OBIEE, but worth recording for people coming along to it new.
Doc ID 1068266.1 states:
 UDML is not supported in OBI 10g.
in 11g, XUDML (the Oracle BI Server XML API) will be fully supported and documented.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing OBIEE Systems Management JMX for remote access</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/securing-obiee-systems-management-jmx-for-remote-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/securing-obiee-systems-management-jmx-for-remote-access/</guid>
      <description>JMX OBIEE&amp;rsquo;s Systems Management functionality exposes performance counters and the application&amp;rsquo;s configuration options through Java MBeans and optionally a protocol called JMX.
It&amp;rsquo;s extremely useful, and is documented pretty widely :
 JConsole / JMX JConsole / JMX – followup Oracle BI Management / Systems Management MBeans PerfMon OBIEE MBeans and OC4J OBIEE performance monitoring and alerting with jManage  In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss the use of JMX to access these counters remotely, and a possible security issue that&amp;rsquo;s present in the BI Management Pack manual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s been at the cookie jar? EBS-BI authentication and Load Balancers</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/whos-been-at-the-cookie-jar-ebs-bi-authentication-and-load-balancers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/whos-been-at-the-cookie-jar-ebs-bi-authentication-and-load-balancers/</guid>
      <description>We hit a very interesting problem in our Production environment recently. We&amp;rsquo;d made no changes for a long time to the configuration, but all of a sudden users were on the phone complaining. They could login to BI from EBS but after logging in the next link they clicked took them to the OBIEE &amp;ldquo;You are not logged in&amp;rdquo; screen.
Our users login to EBS R12 and then using EBS authentication log in to OBIEE (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Support blog no more</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/02/15/oracle-support-blog-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/02/15/oracle-support-blog-no-more/</guid>
      <description>A sad little passing last week, of the Oracle Support Blog and related tweets by Chris Warticki.
Last week Chris posted this comment on twitter
 &amp;ldquo;So, what to do if you&amp;rsquo;re the &amp;ldquo;online customer presence&amp;rdquo; and your own leadership wants to censor your posts and comments?&amp;quot;
 followed by this terse blog posting:
 Support Blog: No longer available
By chris.warticki on February 12, 2010 4:08 PM Please use My Oracle Support Communities instead</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exadata V2 POC numbers</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/02/10/exadata-v2-poc-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/02/10/exadata-v2-poc-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across this blog posting recently, and am reposting the link here as I&amp;rsquo;ve seen no mention of it elsewhere. This surprised me as with Exadata (and most new technologies) any snippet of news or tech insight gets blogged and tweeted multiple times over.
Any insight into Exadata is interesting as unlike all the other Oracle software which can be downloaded and poked &amp;amp; prodded, this is a physical box so we rely on blog postings and marketing (with a BS filter) to understand more about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify your OBIEE users by setting Client ID in Oracle connection</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/26/identify-your-obiee-users-by-setting-client-id-in-oracle-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/26/identify-your-obiee-users-by-setting-client-id-in-oracle-connection/</guid>
      <description>You get a call from your friendly DBA. He says the production database is up the spout, and it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;that bee eye thingumy causing it&amp;rdquo;. What do you do now? All you&amp;rsquo;ve got to go on is a program name in the Oracle session tables of &amp;ldquo;nqsserver@MYSERVER (TNS V1-V3)&amp;rdquo; and the SQL the DBA sent you that if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky will look as presentable as this: The username against the SQL is the generic User ID that you had created for connections to the database from OBIEE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to resolve &#34;[nQSError: 12002] Socket communication error at call=: (Number=-1) Unknown&#34;</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/22/how-to-resolve-nqserror-12002-socket-communication-error-at-call-number-1-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/22/how-to-resolve-nqserror-12002-socket-communication-error-at-call-number-1-unknown/</guid>
      <description>This error caught me out today. I was building a Linux VM to do some work on, and for the life of me couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the OBIEE Admin Tool to connect to the BI Server on the VM.
The error I got when trying to define a DSN on the Windows box was:
 [nQSError: 12008] Unable to connect to port 9703 on machine 10.3.105.132 [nQSError: 12010] Communication error connecting to remote end point: address = 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>libnnz10.so: cannot restore segment prot after reloc: Permission denied</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/18/libnnz10.so-cannot-restore-segment-prot-after-reloc-permission-denied/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/18/libnnz10.so-cannot-restore-segment-prot-after-reloc-permission-denied/</guid>
      <description>Quick post as the snow&amp;rsquo;s coming down and I wanna go home &amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on building a VM based on OEL5.4 and OBIEE 10.1.3.4.1. After installing XE 10.2 I tried to fire my RPD up, but hit this:
 /usr/lib/oracle/xe/app/oracle/product/10.2.0/server/lib/libnnz10.so: cannot restore segment prot after reloc: Permission denied [nQSError: 46029] Failed to load the DLL /app/oracle/product/obiee/server/Bin/libnqsdbgatewayoci10g.so. Check if &amp;lsquo;Oracle OCI 10G&amp;rsquo; database client is installed.
 If you trace the &amp;lsquo;stack&amp;rsquo; back you find that it parses down to this nub of an error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the OBIEE admin tool on Unix</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/14/running-the-obiee-admin-tool-on-unix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/14/running-the-obiee-admin-tool-on-unix/</guid>
      <description>Mucho kudos to Borkur Steingrimsson for getting the OBIEE admin tool working on Unix!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAF</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/11/caf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/11/caf/</guid>
      <description>Very interesting post by Kevin McGinley about CAF here: CAF = Migration Utility? Use Caution!
It articulates better than I ever could reasons against using CAF particularly in a production environment.
Since the tool came out I&amp;rsquo;d been struggling to get my head around it, convinced I was missing something. I still don&amp;rsquo;t profess to understand it properly, but Kevin&amp;rsquo;s article reassures me that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be losing too much sleep over it, especially given that it&amp;rsquo;s unsupported and won&amp;rsquo;t work with 11g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Presentation Services / analytics connectivity</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/09/troubleshooting-presentation-services-/-analytics-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/09/troubleshooting-presentation-services-/-analytics-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>Short but sweet this one - a way of troubleshooting connectivity problems between analytics (the Presentation Services Plug-in, either j2ee servlet or ISAPI, a.k.a. SAWBridge) and sawserver (Presentation Services).
For a recap on the services &amp;amp; flow please see the first few paragraphs of this post.
Problems in connectivity between analytics and sawserver normally manifest themselves through this error message:
 500 Internal Server Error Servlet error: An exception occurred. The current application deployment descriptors do not allow for including it in this response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UKOUG TEBS 2009</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/03/ukoug-tebs-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/12/03/ukoug-tebs-2009/</guid>
      <description>This was my first UKOUG TEBS, in fact my first conference I&amp;rsquo;d ever attended! I was quite unsure what to expect, but three days later I can safely say it was invaluable.
The variety of presentations and expertise being shared was impressive, and it was great to hear people sharing and discussing their ideas and opinions around the subjects I work with each day.
Working in isolation is not a good idea, one can develop a blinkered or bunker mentality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE application servers, now and future</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/25/obiee-application-servers-now-and-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/25/obiee-application-servers-now-and-future/</guid>
      <description>Oracle have published an interesting doc 968223.1, entitled &amp;ldquo;Enterprise Deployment of Oracle BI EE on OC4J and App Servers&amp;rdquo;.
It details the differences between OC4J and OAS which is useful for the current versions of OBIEE. It then also gives a useful heads-up &amp;ndash; that WebLogic becomes the App server of choice in the next version of OBIEE
 All of this changes in OBI EE 11g where several projects will become absolutely dependent upon an App Server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoOotW and sweep</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/25/soootw-and-sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/25/soootw-and-sweep/</guid>
      <description>(Sorry for the lame title, but it gives me an excuse to put this picture in :) )
I was really pleased by the response I got from my posting about The state of OBIEE on the web, knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s not just me goes a long way to keeping my blood pressure down.
The OTN forum is still an unbalanced mix of tosh (is this guy for real?) with the occasional insightful and interesting post or idea such as this really neat one from Joe Bertram about using multiple presentation services on top of the same RPD to give different interfaces to different end devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition on Sun Systems</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/12/deploying-oracle-business-intelligence-enterprise-edition-on-sun-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/12/deploying-oracle-business-intelligence-enterprise-edition-on-sun-systems/</guid>
      <description>A very interesting new PDF from Sun on deploying OBIEE has been published, with discussions on architecture, performance and best practice.
 This Sun BluePrints article describes an enterprise deployment architecture for Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition using Sun servers running the Solaris Operating System and Sun Storage 7000 Unified Storage systems. Designed to empower employees in organizations in any industry—from customer service, shipping, and finance to manufacturing, human resources, and more—to become potential decision makers, the architecture brings fault tolerance, security, resiliency, and performance to enterprise deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE clustering - specifying multiple Presentation Services from Presentation Services Plug-in</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/06/obiee-clustering-specifying-multiple-presentation-services-from-presentation-services-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/06/obiee-clustering-specifying-multiple-presentation-services-from-presentation-services-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Whilst the BI Cluster Controller takes care nicely of clustering and failover for BI Server (nqsserver), we have to do more to ensure further resilience of the stack.
A diagram I come back to again and again when working out configuration or connectivity problems is the one on P16 of the Deployment Guide. With this you can work out most issues for yourself through simple reasoning. Print it out, pin it to your wall, and read it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Googling for OBIEE information</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/03/advanced-googling-for-obiee-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/03/advanced-googling-for-obiee-information/</guid>
      <description>Want to find all PDFs from Oracle about OBIEE?

There&amp;rsquo;s some interesting ones that this turned up on Oracle&amp;rsquo;s public FTP. In particular:
 BI EE Environmental and Multi-User Development Migration Processes Securing Oracle BI Enterprise Edition  (There&amp;rsquo;s also PowerPoint files on there including this one but Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to index them)
You can use Google&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Search page to build similar queries:
You can also use Google Alerts so that any time a new entry matching your search criteria is added in Google&amp;rsquo;s index you get notified of it either by email or on an RSS feed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAF installation video</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/03/caf-installation-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/03/caf-installation-video/</guid>
      <description>Christian Screen has done a nice video explaining the CAF installation, and has promised a deep-dive followup which I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to. Click here for the article</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of OBIEE on the web</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/30/the-state-of-obiee-on-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/30/the-state-of-obiee-on-the-web/</guid>
      <description>An advance footnote I&amp;rsquo;ll start this by saying why I think things are how they are, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll get to the meat of my article.
OBIEE in its current incarnation (v10.1.3) is a mature product. All the big bugs have been caught and fixed. All the known quirks are well documented. All the missing features are known. All the clever workarounds have been found. All the neat little hacks have been explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting OBIEE and ORA-12154: TNS:could not resolve the connect identifier</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/22/troubleshooting-obiee-and-ora-12154-tnscould-not-resolve-the-connect-identifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/22/troubleshooting-obiee-and-ora-12154-tnscould-not-resolve-the-connect-identifier/</guid>
      <description>A frequent question on the OTN OBIEE forum is how to fix this error:
 [nQSError: 17001] Oracle Error code: 12154, message: ORA-12154: TNS:could not resolve the connect identifier specified at OCI call OCIServerAttach. [nQSError: 17014] Could not connect to Oracle database.
 The error is simply OBIEE reporting that it tried to connect from the BI Server to an Oracle database and the Oracle client returned an error. Distilling it down gives us this error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Patch Update - OBIEE vuln CVE-2009-1990</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/21/critical-patch-update-obiee-vuln-cve-2009-1990/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/21/critical-patch-update-obiee-vuln-cve-2009-1990/</guid>
      <description>October&amp;rsquo;s Oracle Critical Patch Update Advisory has been released. There are two vulnerabilities (CVE-2009-1999, CVE-2009-1990) listed under Oracle Application Server for &amp;ldquo;Component&amp;rdquo; Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition and one (CVE-2009-3407) for &amp;ldquo;component&amp;rdquo; Portal.
 CVE-2009-1999 is OBIEE and &amp;ldquo;Fixed in all supported versions. No patch provided in this Critical Patch Update.&amp;rdquo;. CVE-2009-3407 looks like only OAS (not OBIEE), up to versions 10.1.2.3 and 10.1.4.2. CVE-2009-1990 is OBIEE and is the main vuln of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New OBIEE blogs</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/19/new-obiee-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/19/new-obiee-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Two new blogs of note :
 Shiv Bharti&amp;rsquo;s Blog Debashis&amp;rsquo;s OBIEE Blog  Both are well worth a read &amp;amp; following.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BI Server hung - nQSError 14054 / 15001 / 23005</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/16/bi-server-hung-nqserror-14054-/-15001-/-23005/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/16/bi-server-hung-nqserror-14054-/-15001-/-23005/</guid>
      <description>Watch out if you are using init blocks in your RPD. We hit a bug (#9019374) recently that caused BI Server (10.1.3.4) to hang.
The init block in question should have returned a date to update a repository variable, but because of badly-written SQL and abnormal data in the source table actually returned a null value. BI Server evidently didn&amp;rsquo;t like this null being inserted somewhere where it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have and understandably logged :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heads up - Critical Patch Update affecting OBIEE</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/16/heads-up-critical-patch-update-affecting-obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/16/heads-up-critical-patch-update-affecting-obiee/</guid>
      <description>The Critical Patch Update Pre-Release Announcement for October has been published. The pre-release is advance notice of the affected software prior to release of the quarterly Critical Patch Update. It is published on the Thursday prior to the patch releases (which was postponed by a week because of OOW).
It looks like if you&amp;rsquo;re running OBIEE 10.1.3.4.0 or 10.1.3.4.1 through OAS 10.1.2.3.0/10.1.3.4.0/10.1.3.5.0 then you should check back next Tuesday 20th for details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New OBIEE benchmark - 50,000 users</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/12/new-obiee-benchmark-50000-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/12/new-obiee-benchmark-50000-users/</guid>
      <description>A new OBIEE benchmark has been published by Oracle. It&amp;rsquo;s on the same hardware as August&amp;rsquo;s benchmark - Sun T5440s. Anyone would think that Oracle like Sun ;-)
Details here
Numbers added to my collation post here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usage Tracking - only half the story ...</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/06/usage-tracking-only-half-the-story-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/06/usage-tracking-only-half-the-story-.../</guid>
      <description>OBIEE comes with a very useful usage tracking feature. For information about it and how to set it up see these links:
 http://obiee101.blogspot.com/2008/08/obiee-setting-up-usage-tracking.html http://www.oracle.com/technology/obe/obe_bi/bi_ee_1013/usage_tracking/usage_tracking.htm http://108obiee.blogspot.com/2009/07/obiee-usage-tracking-setup-and-cloning.html  Usage Tracking captures the logical SQL of queries in a column called QUERY_TEXT in the table S_NQ_ACCT. However, out of the box this column is defined as 1k (1024 bytes) long. In some situations this will limit its usefulness because the text will be truncated if necessary when it&amp;rsquo;s inserted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and HP Performance Center (a.k.a. LoadRunner) - Notes</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/obiee-and-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/obiee-and-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner-notes/</guid>
      <description>This is a supplemental post to this one describing how to set up a VUser in LoadRunner to test OBIEE. It&amp;rsquo;s various notes that I made during the development but which aren&amp;rsquo;t directly part of the step-by-step tutorial. They&amp;rsquo;re not necessarily vital for recording scripts, but observations and explanations that should be helpful when working with LoadRunner and OBIEE.
Validation using sawserver logs It&amp;rsquo;s no use running a load test if the load you think you&amp;rsquo;re applying isn&amp;rsquo;t actually being applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing OBIEE using HP Performance Center (a.k.a. LoadRunner)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/</guid>
      <description>My two earlier posts (here and here) detail the difficulties I had with LoadRunner (now called HP Performance Center). After a bit of a break along with encouragement from knowing that it must be possible because it&amp;rsquo;s how Oracle generates their OBIEE benchmarks I&amp;rsquo;ve now got something working. I also got a useful doc from Oracle support which outlines pretty much what I&amp;rsquo;ve done here too.
In essence what you do - and what the Metalink document 496417.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collated OBIEE benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/18/collated-obiee-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/18/collated-obiee-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>(Updated 12th Oct 09)
Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the OBIEE benchmark documents published by Oracle:
BenchmarkDateSource document1 - IBM System x3755Sep-07PDF2 - HP DL380 G4Sep-07PDF3 - Sun T2000Sep-07PDF4 - Sun SPARC Enterprise T5440Aug-09PDF5 - Sun SPARC Enterprise T5440Oct-09PDF Collecting the numbers into one table gives this: 
Based on the details in the documents I think these were all against OBIA&amp;rsquo;s Service Analytics schema &amp;amp; dashboards/reports.
Interesting to note the side-by-side comparison in benchmark 3 (Sun T2000) of two servers, in one case both running BI and Presentation Services and in the other having the two components separate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/17/obiee-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/17/obiee-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the OBIEE benchmark documents published by Oracle:
  28,000 User Benchmark on Sun SPARC Enterprise T5440 Server running Solaris 10 [Aug 09]
  10,000 User Benchmark on Sun T2000 [Sept 07]
  5,800 User Benchmark on HP DL380 G4 [Sept 07]
  4,000 User Benchmark on an IBM System x3755 Server running Red Hat Enterprise Linux
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE cluster controller failover in action</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/15/obiee-cluster-controller-failover-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/15/obiee-cluster-controller-failover-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Production cluster is 2x BI Server and 2x Presentation Services, with a BIG-IP F5 load balancer on the front.
Symptoms Users started reporting slow login times to BI. Our monitoring tool (Openview) reported that &amp;ldquo;BIServer01 may be down. Failed to contact it using ping.&amp;rdquo;. BIServer01 cannot be reached by ping or ssh from Windows network.
Diagnostics nqsserver and nqsclustercontroller on BIServer01 was logging these repeated errors:
 [nQSError: 12002] Socket communication error at call=send: (Number=9) Bad file number</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE on Opera 10 / IE 7 / FF 3.5 / Chrome 4</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/10/obiee-on-opera-10-/-ie-7-/-ff-3.5-/-chrome-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/10/obiee-on-opera-10-/-ie-7-/-ff-3.5-/-chrome-4/</guid>
      <description>A new version of the web browser Opera was released recently. Several years ago I used Opera and may even have paid for it IIRC. Then Firefox came along, and the &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not IE&amp;rdquo; excuse was lost for Opera. Not that I mind IE too much nowadays but at the time it was atrocious. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve revisited Opera each time a new release has come out, but nothing has impressed me enough to ditch Firefox (and nowadays Google Chrome).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdminTool.exe /command</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/08/admintool.exe-/command/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/08/admintool.exe-/command/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s an undocumented feature in AdminTool.exe that you can use the /command switch with a text file containing scripted commands to make changes to an RPD file (or create a new one).
It&amp;rsquo;s undocumented and UNSUPPORTED so be careful using it.
Some good details in these blog posts, especially Erik&amp;rsquo;s which has a good list of syntax.
 Venkat Erik Eckhardt (translated from Czech, original here) @lex Kumar Kambam  I&amp;rsquo;m intrigued to know how the original posters figured out the commands available, if it&amp;rsquo;s undocumented&amp;hellip; :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS feeds for OBIEE, including del.icio.us obiee tags</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/04/rss-feeds-for-obiee-including-del.icio.us-obiee-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/04/rss-feeds-for-obiee-including-del.icio.us-obiee-tags/</guid>
      <description>Another way of keeping up with what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the obiee world, add this RSS feed of del.icio.us obiee tags to your reader. It may be less &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; (because people might discover and bookmark &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; pages), but it&amp;rsquo;s another tool in the armoury :)
If you want an aggregated RSS feed of OBIEE / Oracle related blog postings try this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAF troubles</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/03/caf-troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/03/caf-troubles/</guid>
      <description>Following the Oracle CAF tutorial here, I got to Cloning Answers Requests section and then got stuck. I&amp;rsquo;d set up my environment exactly the same as in the tutorial, down to the same paths etc. After firing up the CAF to clone requests from the SampleSales catalog: I clicked on Next and got the error &amp;ldquo;Exception occurred when while initializing repository!!!&amp;quot;
By playing around with the passwords and path names I determined that both RPD files existed and that CAF could load them enough to validate the passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metalink 3 RIP</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/02/metalink-3-rip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/02/metalink-3-rip/</guid>
      <description>This weekend just gone Metalink3 went to the digital dustbin. In principle this is a Good Thing, as multiple support websites for a single company is confusing and frustrating.
Metalink is now &amp;ldquo;My Oracle Support&amp;rdquo; and is a flash-based whizz-bang affair. Everyone has different tastes, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to be said for plain HTML for ease and speed of access. But then people probably grumbled to the Wright Brothers that there was nothing wrong with land-transport at the time&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple RPDs on one server - Part 1 - the BI Server</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/25/multiple-rpds-on-one-server-part-1-the-bi-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/25/multiple-rpds-on-one-server-part-1-the-bi-server/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article I plan to get samplesales and paint repositories hosted on a single server, using one BI Server instance and two Presentation Services instances. This is on both Unix (OEL 4) and Windows, and both OC4J (OBIEE&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;basic installation&amp;rdquo; option) and OAS (&amp;ldquo;Advanced Installation&amp;rdquo;).
Both samplesales and paint are shipped with 10.1.3.4 of OBIEE, you&amp;rsquo;ll find them in $OracleBI/OracleBI/server/Sample. This article assumes you&amp;rsquo;ve got the RPD of each into $OracleBI/OracleBI/server/Repository and unpacked the web cats for each into $OracleBIdata/web/catalog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple RPDs on one server - Part 2 - Presentation Services</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/25/multiple-rpds-on-one-server-part-2-presentation-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/25/multiple-rpds-on-one-server-part-2-presentation-services/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this article I plan to get sample and paint repositories hosted on a single server, using one BI Server instance and two Presentation Services instances. This is on both Unix (OEL 4) and Windows, and both OC4J (OBIEE&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;basic installation&amp;rdquo; option) and OAS (&amp;ldquo;Advanced Installation&amp;rdquo;).
Make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve read and followed part 1 - BI Server first.
Remember that multiple Presentation Services instances on a machine is UNSUPPORTED BY ORACLE!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE error/message code reference</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/24/obiee-error/message-code-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/24/obiee-error/message-code-reference/</guid>
      <description>For some reason Oracle haven&amp;rsquo;t put out a 10.x version of the error &amp;amp; message codes reference guide for OBIEE, but the previous version for Siebel Analytics is still useful:
 PDF version: http://download.oracle.com/otndocs/products/bi/bi-ee/docs/784/AnyMsg.pdf HTML version: http://download.oracle.com/docs/cd/E12103_01/books/AnyMsg/AnyMsg_Messages.html#wp1007961  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and Load Runner - part 2</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/obiee-and-load-runner-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/obiee-and-load-runner-part-2/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED: See a HOWTO for OBIEE and LoadRunner here: /2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/
 This is following on from my first post about OBIEE and LoadRunner, in which I failed dismally to get a simple session replaying.
In a nutshell where I&amp;rsquo;d got to was using the &amp;ldquo;Web (Click and Script)&amp;rdquo; function which worked fine for logging in but when running a report resulted in an error on the rendered page. Digging around showed the error was from the javascript of the OBIEE front end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Querying SQL Server from OBIEE running on Unix</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/querying-sql-server-from-obiee-running-on-unix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/querying-sql-server-from-obiee-running-on-unix/</guid>
      <description>A question that pops up on the OBIEE OTN forum quite often is how to use non-Oracle databases like MS SQL Server when the OBIEE server is running on a non-Windows OS such as Linux.
The answer in a nutshell is that since version 10.1.3.3.1 OBIEE has been bundled with ODBC drivers for unix/linux from a company called DataDirect. See the release notes here for more information and installation instructions (as well as a list of support databases).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and Load Runner - part 1</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/obiee-and-load-runner-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/obiee-and-load-runner-part-1/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED: See a HOWTO for OBIEE and LoadRunner here
 Introduction LoadRunner is a tool from HP (bought from Mercury) that can be used to simulate user activity. It supports a whole host of protocols but for OBIEE I&amp;rsquo;m obviously using the Web one.
There are two flavours, &amp;ldquo;Web (Click and Script)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Web (HTTP/HTML)&amp;rdquo;. The latter simply shoves HTTP requests at the server, whereas &amp;ldquo;Click and Script&amp;rdquo; simulates mouse and keyboard entry and thus is more appropriate for this user-based application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unix script to report on OBIEE and OBIA processes state</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/14/unix-script-to-report-on-obiee-and-obia-processes-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/14/unix-script-to-report-on-obiee-and-obia-processes-state/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a set of scripts that I use on our servers as a quick way to check if the various BI components are up and running.
Because we split the stack across servers, there are different scripts called in combination. On our dev boxes we have everything and so the script calls all three sub-scripts, whereas on Production each server will run one of:
 BI Server Presentation Server &amp;amp; OAS Informatica &amp;amp; DAC  The scripts source another script called process_check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is OBIA...</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/30/what-is-obia.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/30/what-is-obia.../</guid>
      <description>Very good post by @lex giving a nice clear explanation of what OBIA (Oracle Business Intelligence Applications) is
http://siebel-essentials.blogspot.com/2009/06/can-you-describe-oracle-bi-applications.html
This should be made a sticky on the OBIA forum in my opinion.
It&amp;rsquo;s clear from postings on the forum that an awful lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t understand what OBIA is or how it sits with OBIEE. I even attended a course last week in which the Oracle trainer stated that OBIEE included ETL and DW schemas, and stuck to this when challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE performance monitoring and alerting with jManage</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/29/obiee-performance-monitoring-and-alerting-with-jmanage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/29/obiee-performance-monitoring-and-alerting-with-jmanage/</guid>
      <description>OBIEE&amp;rsquo;s Systems Management component exposes configuration and performance data through Java MBeans. As discussed in other posts these can be be accessed through several different ways:
 JConsole (see also here) oc4j Windows PerfMon (although I guess this isn&amp;rsquo;t actually using MBeans/JMX?) saw.dll?perfmon BI Management Pack  Since it&amp;rsquo;s a standard java technology being used we can in theory use anything that is designed for monitoring mbeans via jmx. Doing some Googling I discovered jManage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find out what web application server is in use</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/28/how-to-find-out-what-web-application-server-is-in-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/28/how-to-find-out-what-web-application-server-is-in-use/</guid>
      <description>If, for some reason, you need to check what web application server is in use for Presentation Services (as this chap needed to), you can use an add-in for FireFox called HttpFox to inspect the HTTP headers.
1. Install HttpFox (and obviously Firefox if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it already!)
2. Open the HttpFox window (Tools -&amp;gt; HttpFox -&amp;gt; Toggle HttpFox)
3. Click the Start button in the HttpFox window
4. Navigate to your OBIEE home page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE Windows PerfMon counters</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/24/obiee-windows-perfmon-counters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/24/obiee-windows-perfmon-counters/</guid>
      <description>Yet another way to access the BI Management data discussed here - through Windows&#39; PerfMon tool.
This will only work for installations where your OBIEE server is running on Windows. You should be able to run PerfMon locally or remotely. Standard practise would be not to run it locally on a Production machine :-)
To run PerfMon go to Start-&amp;gt;Run and enter perfmon, or navigate Start -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Control Panel -&amp;gt; Administrative Tools -&amp;gt; Performance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Rittman&#39;s OBIEE repository for DAC</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/mark-rittmans-obiee-repository-for-dac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/mark-rittmans-obiee-repository-for-dac/</guid>
      <description>Mark Rittman has an excellent article about querying the DAC repository database tables, including a downloadable RPD file. Being new to working with RPDs I thought it would be good practise to explore this as well as hopefully get some useful information about our current ETL deployment.
I downloaded the RPD to c:\OracleBI\server\Repository and opened it up in the Admin tool (Administrator/Administrator).
First off I changed the connection pool to point to my DAC repository database, having setup a TNS entry for it first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>psservice - Windows command line goodness!</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/psservice-windows-command-line-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/psservice-windows-command-line-goodness/</guid>
      <description>Our main servers are Unix and I&amp;rsquo;m as happy as a pig in muck at the command line, so when I&amp;rsquo;m working on Windows (where I&amp;rsquo;ve got a test OBIEE install) I like to stick with the CLI where possible.
PSService is one of those tools that I instinctively reach for without realising it. Combined with Launchy, it&amp;rsquo;s even better.
Simply put, you can control windows services from the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sawserver charts crash</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/sawserver-charts-crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/sawserver-charts-crash/</guid>
      <description>By a strange co-incidence after following this thread on OTN forums about a BI crash and struggling to understand the actual problem, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered it myself!
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a test install of OBIEE running on my Windows XP laptop, and whilst building a report in Answers got this:
](http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_RCx_EVJpczQ/SmiDrEorbbI/AAAAAAAAGcg/OPGwTLXXg8k/s1600/crash1.png)[![](/images/rnm1978/crash2.png) was:
 szAppName : sawserver.exe szAppVer : 10.1.3.4 szModName : kernel32.dll szModVer : 5.1.2600.3119 offset : 000097a3
 Going to the sawserver log at c:\OracleBIData\web\log\sawlog0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JConsole / JMX - followup</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/jconsole-/-jmx-followup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/jconsole-/-jmx-followup/</guid>
      <description>A few points to add to my previous posting on JConsole:
 As well as performance data, you have access to configuration data. Be aware that it is read-write! So whilst it might be a nice alternative to digging around for your instanceconfig.xml etc, you should be careful If you have your BI Server and Presentation Services deployed on separate servers then you will only get MBeans for the relevant service:   If you want to view the values of the BI Server MBeans and your Presentation Services server is not on the same box then you have to use JConsole/JMX, as Performance Monitor will not have access to the values:  ](http://2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE admin tools &amp;amp; hacks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/obiee-admin-tools-amp-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/obiee-admin-tools-amp-hacks/</guid>
      <description>As a kid I loved the idea of lego where you can disassemble and reassemble something from the ground up. As soon as I got my hands on a computer it was the same. You can have your Acorn Archimedes with its games, where do I find the sprites and sound files behind it? Likewise Microsoft Word, let me at the VBA underneath to hack it around and see what else it can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JConsole / JMX</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/16/jconsole-/-jmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/16/jconsole-/-jmx/</guid>
      <description>[edit] See this post too [/edit] On an OBIEE server run [sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;] nohup obiee/systemsmanagement/runagent.sh &amp;amp; [/sourcecode] and then run jconsole (make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve set the DISPLAY first if you&amp;rsquo;re running it from UNIX). NB: if you don&amp;rsquo;t have jconsole in your path you can search for it: [sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;] $whereis jconsole jconsole: /opt/java1.5/bin/jconsole /opt/java6/bin/jconsole&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; [/sourcecode] You should find it under your java/bin directory
You should get this kind of connection dialog:  Click connect, and the console will launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nqcmd and [nQSError: 27005] Unresolved column</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/05/28/nqcmd-and-nqserror-27005-unresolved-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/05/28/nqcmd-and-nqserror-27005-unresolved-column/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a scripted load test for OBIEE using nqcmd to run reports multiple times. I hit this interesting issue.
Cut and pasting the logical SQL that Presentation Services sends to BI Server from Manage Sessions -&amp;gt; Statement, I kept getting this error when I ran it through nqcmd:
 [10058][State: S1000] [NQODBC] [SQL_STATE: S1000] [nQSError: 10058] A general error has occurred.
[nQSError: 27005] Unresolved column: &amp;ldquo;Natural Account (COA)&amp;rdquo;.&amp;ldquo;Account Parent1 Code&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom HTTP error page in OBIEE / OAS</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/05/18/custom-http-error-page-in-obiee-/-oas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/05/18/custom-http-error-page-in-obiee-/-oas/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s possible to change the error pages served up by OAS/Apache by using the ErrorDocument directive. This is widely documented.
However, to get this to take effect in an oc4j application (such as analytics) you need to change mod_oc4j.conf too.
(I found this out from this post here)
Take backups of httpd.conf and mod_oc4j.conf, and then edit them as follows:
In httpd.conf add:
ErrorDocument 500 /500.html
where /500.html is a relative path to your custom document</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New releases</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/28/new-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/28/new-releases/</guid>
      <description>New releases this week - 10.1.3.4.1 of OBIEE, and 7.9.6 of OBIA.
After a bit of scrabbling around found:

 &amp;ldquo;The 10.1.3.4.1 release of the Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition introduces no new features.&amp;quot;
 Though there are some new bits and pieces for Publisher
For 7.9.6 OBIA, there&amp;rsquo;s no New Features document :(
By piecing together the &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s New in This Release&amp;rdquo; for each document you can build up a picture (eg in the Upgrade Guide there&amp;rsquo;s reference to changes for the doc relating to a new version of Informatica), but it would be nice to have it all in one place:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and F5 BIG-IP</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/15/obiee-and-f5-big-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/15/obiee-and-f5-big-ip/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve got a setup of two OAS/Presentation Services boxes and two BI Server boxes, with load balancing/failover throughout.
The Load Balancing of the web requests is being done through a separate bit of kit, an F5 BIG-IP load balancer. This directs the requests at the two OAS servers.
The problem we have is that by default OAS serves HTTP on port 7777, but the F5 is using port 80. A request for our load balanced URL: http://bi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sawserver won&#39;t start up - resolved</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/01/sawserver-wont-start-up-resolved/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/01/sawserver-wont-start-up-resolved/</guid>
      <description>(See here and here for history)
I edited the shell script which is eventually called by run-saw.sh to start the sawserver, (OracleBI)/setup/sawserver.sh, to use trus:
Comment out the final line:
 $SASAWSERVER
 and insert as a new line:
 tusc -fepan -o /tmp/sawserver_tusc.out $SASAWSERVER
 The output of trus ended with this:
 open(&amp;quot;/app/oracle/product/10.2.0/lib/libstd_v2.so.1&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|0x800, 0) &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; ERR#2 ENOENT
open(&amp;quot;/app/oracle/product/obiee/server/Bin64/libstd_v2.so.1&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|0x800, 0) . ERR#2 ENOENT
open(&amp;quot;/app/oracle/product/obiee/web/bin64/libstd_v2.so.1&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|0x800, 0) &amp;hellip;. ERR#2 ENOENT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sawserver won&#39;t start (analytics: Servlet error java.net.ConnectException: Connection refused (errno:239))</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/30/sawserver-wont-start-analytics-servlet-error-java.net.connectexception-connection-refused-errno239/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/30/sawserver-wont-start-analytics-servlet-error-java.net.connectexception-connection-refused-errno239/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re getting this error in the Presentation Services plug-in [analytics].
Log file: /j2ee/home/application-deployments/analytics/home_default_group_1/application.log
 09/03/30 13:16:38.75 analytics: Servlet error
java.net.ConnectException: Connection refused (errno:239)
at java.net.PlainSocketImpl.socketConnect(Native Method)
at java.net.PlainSocketImpl.doConnect(PlainSocketImpl.java:333)
at java.net.PlainSocketImpl.connectToAddress(PlainSocketImpl.java:195)
at java.net.PlainSocketImpl.connect(PlainSocketImpl.java:182)
at java.net.SocksSocketImpl.connect(SocksSocketImpl.java:366)
at java.net.Socket.connect(Socket.java:517)
at java.net.Socket.connect(Socket.java:467)
at java.net.Socket.(Socket.java:364)
at java.net.Socket.(Socket.java:178)
at com.siebel.analytics.web.sawconnect.ConnectionPoolSocketFactoryImpl.createSocket(ConnectionPoolSocketFactoryImpl.java:63)
at sun.reflect.NativeMethodAccessorImpl.invoke0(Native Method)
at sun.reflect.NativeMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(NativeMethodAccessorImpl.java:39)
at sun.reflect.DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.invoke(DelegatingMethodAccessorImpl.java:25)
at java.lang.reflect.Method.invoke(Method.java:585)
at com.siebel.analytics.web.sawconnect.ConnectionPoolSocketFactoryImpl.createSocket(ConnectionPoolSocketFactoryImpl.java:70)
at com.siebel.analytics.web.sawconnect.ConnectionPool.createNewConnection(ConnectionPool.java:314)
at com.siebel.analytics.web.sawconnect.ConnectionPool.getConnection(ConnectionPool.java:133)
at com.siebel.analytics.web.SAWBridge.processRequest(SAWBridge.java:299)
at com.siebel.analytics.web.SAWBridge.doGet(SAWBridge.java:325)
at javax.servlet.http.HttpServlet.service(HttpServlet.java:743)
at javax.servlet.http.HttpServlet.service(HttpServlet.java:856)
at com.evermind[Oracle Containers for J2EE 10g (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Publisher - Scheduler and Report Repository</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/24/clustering-publisher-scheduler-and-report-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/24/clustering-publisher-scheduler-and-report-repository/</guid>
      <description>The Oracle BI Publisher Enterprise Cluster Deployment doc which I just found through Metalink highlighted a couple of points:
- Report repository should be shared
- The scheduler should be configured for a cluster
Report Repository
Through Admin&amp;gt;System Maintenance&amp;gt;Report Repository I changed the path from the default, /xmlp/XMLP to a NFS mount data/shared/xmlp and restarted the xmlpserver application in OAS. On coming back up Publisher complained because all its config files (in xmlp/Admin), had disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which jdbc driver to use</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/24/which-jdbc-driver-to-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/24/which-jdbc-driver-to-use/</guid>
      <description>In setting the scheduler in Publisher I discovered a useful difference in jdbc drivers.
Our repository is on Oracle 11g.
According to the manual oracle.jdbc.driver.OracleDriver should be used, but previous installations have used oracle.bi.jdbc.AnaJdbcDriver so I tried this too.
In experimenting with both I found you get more useful feedback from the second one. Here&amp;rsquo;s the same problem reported by both drivers:
 · Exception [TOPLINK-4002] (Oracle TopLink - 11g Release 1 (11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE Publisher - configuring connection to clustered BI Server</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/23/obiee-publisher-configuring-connection-to-clustered-bi-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/23/obiee-publisher-configuring-connection-to-clustered-bi-server/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m setting up a clustered OBIEE 10.1.3.4 production environment. There are four servers; two BI Server + Cluster Controller + Scheduler and two OAS + Presentation Services + Publisher. Clustering of BI is configured, now I&amp;rsquo;m setting up the other bits. Today is Publisher.
On publisher instance A connections to the BI Servers directly work fine:
jdbc:oraclebi://serverA.fqdn.company.net:9703/ jdbc:oraclebi://serverB.fqdn.company.net:9703/
both work individually as Connection Strings (with database driver class of oracle.bi.jdbc.AnaJdbcDriver) - verified with &amp;ldquo;Test Connection&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
