<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>loadrunner on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/loadrunner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in loadrunner on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/loadrunner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and HP Performance Center (a.k.a. LoadRunner) - Notes</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/obiee-and-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/obiee-and-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner-notes/</guid>
      <description>This is a supplemental post to this one describing how to set up a VUser in LoadRunner to test OBIEE. It&amp;rsquo;s various notes that I made during the development but which aren&amp;rsquo;t directly part of the step-by-step tutorial. They&amp;rsquo;re not necessarily vital for recording scripts, but observations and explanations that should be helpful when working with LoadRunner and OBIEE.
Validation using sawserver logs It&amp;rsquo;s no use running a load test if the load you think you&amp;rsquo;re applying isn&amp;rsquo;t actually being applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing OBIEE using HP Performance Center (a.k.a. LoadRunner)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/</guid>
      <description>My two earlier posts (here and here) detail the difficulties I had with LoadRunner (now called HP Performance Center). After a bit of a break along with encouragement from knowing that it must be possible because it&amp;rsquo;s how Oracle generates their OBIEE benchmarks I&amp;rsquo;ve now got something working. I also got a useful doc from Oracle support which outlines pretty much what I&amp;rsquo;ve done here too.
In essence what you do - and what the Metalink document 496417.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and Load Runner - part 2</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/obiee-and-load-runner-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/obiee-and-load-runner-part-2/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED: See a HOWTO for OBIEE and LoadRunner here: /2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/
 This is following on from my first post about OBIEE and LoadRunner, in which I failed dismally to get a simple session replaying.
In a nutshell where I&amp;rsquo;d got to was using the &amp;ldquo;Web (Click and Script)&amp;rdquo; function which worked fine for logging in but when running a report resulted in an error on the rendered page. Digging around showed the error was from the javascript of the OBIEE front end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and Load Runner - part 1</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/obiee-and-load-runner-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/obiee-and-load-runner-part-1/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED: See a HOWTO for OBIEE and LoadRunner here
 Introduction LoadRunner is a tool from HP (bought from Mercury) that can be used to simulate user activity. It supports a whole host of protocols but for OBIEE I&amp;rsquo;m obviously using the Web one.
There are two flavours, &amp;ldquo;Web (Click and Script)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Web (HTTP/HTML)&amp;rdquo;. The latter simply shoves HTTP requests at the server, whereas &amp;ldquo;Click and Script&amp;rdquo; simulates mouse and keyboard entry and thus is more appropriate for this user-based application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
