<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>load-balancing on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/load-balancing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in load-balancing on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/load-balancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s been at the cookie jar? EBS-BI authentication and Load Balancers</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/whos-been-at-the-cookie-jar-ebs-bi-authentication-and-load-balancers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/05/whos-been-at-the-cookie-jar-ebs-bi-authentication-and-load-balancers/</guid>
      <description>We hit a very interesting problem in our Production environment recently. We&amp;rsquo;d made no changes for a long time to the configuration, but all of a sudden users were on the phone complaining. They could login to BI from EBS but after logging in the next link they clicked took them to the OBIEE &amp;ldquo;You are not logged in&amp;rdquo; screen.
Our users login to EBS R12 and then using EBS authentication log in to OBIEE (10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE clustering - specifying multiple Presentation Services from Presentation Services Plug-in</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/06/obiee-clustering-specifying-multiple-presentation-services-from-presentation-services-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/06/obiee-clustering-specifying-multiple-presentation-services-from-presentation-services-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Whilst the BI Cluster Controller takes care nicely of clustering and failover for BI Server (nqsserver), we have to do more to ensure further resilience of the stack.
A diagram I come back to again and again when working out configuration or connectivity problems is the one on P16 of the Deployment Guide. With this you can work out most issues for yourself through simple reasoning. Print it out, pin it to your wall, and read it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE cluster controller failover in action</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/15/obiee-cluster-controller-failover-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/15/obiee-cluster-controller-failover-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Production cluster is 2x BI Server and 2x Presentation Services, with a BIG-IP F5 load balancer on the front.
Symptoms Users started reporting slow login times to BI. Our monitoring tool (Openview) reported that &amp;ldquo;BIServer01 may be down. Failed to contact it using ping.&amp;rdquo;. BIServer01 cannot be reached by ping or ssh from Windows network.
Diagnostics nqsserver and nqsclustercontroller on BIServer01 was logging these repeated errors:
[nQSError: 12002] Socket communication error at call=send: (Number=9) Bad file number</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and F5 BIG-IP</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/15/obiee-and-f5-big-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/15/obiee-and-f5-big-ip/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve got a setup of two OAS/Presentation Services boxes and two BI Server boxes, with load balancing/failover throughout.
The Load Balancing of the web requests is being done through a separate bit of kit, an F5 BIG-IP load balancer. This directs the requests at the two OAS servers.
The problem we have is that by default OAS serves HTTP on port 7777, but the F5 is using port 80. A request for our load balanced URL: http://bi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
