<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 17:36:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Where I&#39;ll be on the road for the remainder of 2019</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 17:36:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/09/02/where-ill-be-on-the-road-for-the-remainder-of-2019/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a relaxing couple of weeks off work over the summer, and came back today to realise that I’ve got a fair bit of conference and meetup travel to wrap my head around for the next few months :)
 If you’re interested in where I’ll be and want to come and say hi, hear about Kafka—or just grab a coffee or beer, herewith my itinerary as it currently stands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the Vienna-Munich sleeper train</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/07/03/taking-the-vienna-munich-sleeper-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 07:17:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/07/03/taking-the-vienna-munich-sleeper-train/</guid>
      <description>This week I was scheduled in to a couple of meetups, in Vienna and Munich. Flying is an inevitable part of travel since I also happen to like being home seeing my family and airplanes are usually the quickest way to make this happen. I don’t particularly enjoy flying, and there’s the environmental impact of it too—so when I realised that Vienna and Munich are relatively close to each other I looked at getting the train.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling for Work, with Kids at Home</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/02/09/travelling-for-work-with-kids-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 14:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/02/09/travelling-for-work-with-kids-at-home/</guid>
      <description>I began travelling for my job when my first child was three months old. But don’t mistake correlation for causation…it wasn’t the broken nights&amp;#39; sleep that forced me onto the road, but an excellent job opportunity that seemed worth the risk. Nearly eight years later and I’m in a different job but still with a bunch of travel involved. How much I travel has varied. It’s tended to average around 30%, but has peaked at way more than that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
