<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>config on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/config/</link>
    <description>Recent content in config on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/config/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to resolve &#34;[nQSError: 12002] Socket communication error at call=: (Number=-1) Unknown&#34;</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/22/how-to-resolve-nqserror-12002-socket-communication-error-at-call-number-1-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/22/how-to-resolve-nqserror-12002-socket-communication-error-at-call-number-1-unknown/</guid>
      <description>This error caught me out today. I was building a Linux VM to do some work on, and for the life of me couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the OBIEE Admin Tool to connect to the BI Server on the VM.
The error I got when trying to define a DSN on the Windows box was:
[nQSError: 12008] Unable to connect to port 9703 on machine 10.3.105.132 [nQSError: 12010] Communication error connecting to remote end point: address = 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolved: sawserver : Error loading security privilege /system/privs/catalog/ChangePermissionsPrivilege</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/17/resolved-sawserver-error-loading-security-privilege-/system/privs/catalog/changepermissionsprivilege/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/17/resolved-sawserver-error-loading-security-privilege-/system/privs/catalog/changepermissionsprivilege/</guid>
      <description>Whilst installing OBIA 7.9.6.1 I hit this problem when firing up Presentation Services (sawserver):
Error loading security privilege /system/privs/catalog/ChangePermissionsPrivilege.
A quick search on the forums threw up two posts suggesting a corrupted WebCat.
Since I&amp;rsquo;d got this webcat fresh out of the box I was puzzled how it could be corrupted.
I did a bit more tinkering (including nosying around in the sawserver log), before realising it was indeed corrupt, and that I was indeed a muppet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging specific types of sawserver activity</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/20/logging-specific-types-of-sawserver-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/20/logging-specific-types-of-sawserver-activity/</guid>
      <description>As well as tinkering with the sawserver (Presentation Services) logging level and format, we can specific which bits of the log we&amp;rsquo;re interested in. This is useful for two reasons:
We can enable detailed logging for a specific area, without impacting performance as much as detailed logging throughout would cause By only logging in detail the area of interest we can more easily read the log output and not have to wade through pages of irrelevant information Chapter 9 (“Using the Oracle BI Presentation Services Logging Facility”) of the Presentation Services Administration Guide details the log configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sawserver log - short format</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/sawserver-log-short-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/sawserver-log-short-format/</guid>
      <description>I posted a while ago about the sawserver (Presentation Services) log configuration file. Today I&amp;rsquo;m doing some work digging around why sawserver&amp;rsquo;s throwing an error and so increased the log detail. This parameter is really helpful to use:
fmtName=&amp;ldquo;short&amp;rdquo;
Consider in these two screenshots, the first is with the default log format and shows about six entries. The second is short log format and is about ten times as much data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sawserver logging configuration - logconfig.xml</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/sawserver-logging-configuration-logconfig.xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/23/sawserver-logging-configuration-logconfig.xml/</guid>
      <description>The configuration of how Presentation Services (sawserver) does its logging is in the file web/config/logconfig.xml (same directory as instanceconfig.xml).
It&amp;rsquo;s all nice and XML&amp;rsquo;d:
Logging Detail
Change the numerical values in the FilterRecord entries to alter the detail level of the logging. Lower means less detail, higher means more.
Be aware that your log files can grow very rapidly if you set the logging too high, and unless you&amp;rsquo;re troubleshooting then leave them at the defaults.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
