<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>performance on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/performance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in performance on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Instrumenting OBIEE - the final chapter</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/10/10/instrumenting-obiee-the-final-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/10/10/instrumenting-obiee-the-final-chapter/</guid>
      <description>This article has been superseded by a newer version: Instrumenting OBIEE Database Connections For Improved Performance Diagnostics (Previously on this blog: 1, 2, 3&amp;hellip;)
Summary Instrument your code. Stop guessing. Make your DBA happy. Make your life as a BI Admin easier.
The Problem OBIEE will typically connect to the database using a generic application account. (Hopefully, you&amp;rsquo;ll have isolated it to an account used only for this purpose - if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, you should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quotation to print out and stick on your wall</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/18/a-quotation-to-print-out-and-stick-on-your-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/08/18/a-quotation-to-print-out-and-stick-on-your-wall/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quotation that I&amp;rsquo;ve just read and wanted to share. It is all part of a BAAG approach to troubleshooting problems, performance in particular.
From Greg Rahn (web|twitter) on oracle-l:
There are always exceptions, but exceptions can be justified and supported with data. Just beware of the the silver bullet syndrome&amp;hellip;
The unfortunate part [&amp;hellip;] is that rarely anyone goes back and does the root cause analysis. It tends to fall into the bucket of &amp;ldquo;problem&amp;hellip;solved&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle 11g - How to force a sql_id to use a plan_hash_value using SQL Baselines</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/06/28/oracle-11g-how-to-force-a-sql_id-to-use-a-plan_hash_value-using-sql-baselines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/06/28/oracle-11g-how-to-force-a-sql_id-to-use-a-plan_hash_value-using-sql-baselines/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a scenario that&amp;rsquo;ll be depressingly familiar to most reading this: after ages of running fine, and no changes to the code, a query suddenly starts running for magnitudes longer than it used to.
In this instance it was an ETL step which used to take c.1 hour, and was now at 5 hours and counting. Since it still hadn&amp;rsquo;t finished, and the gods had conspired to bring down Grid too (unrelated), I generated a SQL Monitor report to see what was happening: [sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;sql&amp;rdquo;] select DBMS_SQLTUNE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE performance - get your database sweating</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/05/19/obiee-performance-get-your-database-sweating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/05/19/obiee-performance-get-your-database-sweating/</guid>
      <description>Just because something produces the correct numbers on the report, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you can stop there.
How you are producing those numbers matters, and matters a lot if you have an interest in the long-term health of your system and its ability to scale.
OBIEE is the case in point here, but the principle applies to any architecture with &amp;gt;1 tiers or components.
Let me start with a rhetorical question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting good quality I/O throughput data</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/11/getting-good-quality-i/o-throughput-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/11/getting-good-quality-i/o-throughput-data/</guid>
      <description>This post expands on one I made last year here about sampling frequency (of I/O throughput, but it&amp;rsquo;s a generic concept). The background to this is my analysis of the performance and capacity of our data warehouse on Oracle 11g.
Before I get too boring, here&amp;rsquo;s the fun bit:
Pork Pies per Hour (PP/h) Jim wants to enter a championship pork-pie eating competition. He&amp;rsquo;s timed himself practising and over the course of an hour he eats four pork pies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrumenting OBIEE for tracing Oracle DB calls</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/02/02/instrumenting-obiee-for-tracing-oracle-db-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/02/02/instrumenting-obiee-for-tracing-oracle-db-calls/</guid>
      <description>Cary Millsap recently published a paper &amp;ldquo;Mastering Performance with Extended SQL Trace&amp;rdquo; describing how to use Oracle trace to assist with troubleshooting the performance of database queries. As with all of Cary Millsap&amp;rsquo;s papers it is superbly written, presenting very detailed information in a clear and understandable way. (and yes I do have a DBA crush ;-)) It discusses how you can automate the tracing of specific sessions on the database, and requiring the application to be appropriately instrumented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing ODI batch performance</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/11/03/analysing-odi-batch-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/11/03/analysing-odi-batch-performance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with some performance work around an ODI DWH load batch. The batch comprises well over 1000 tasks in ODI, and whilst the Operator console is not a bad interface, it&amp;rsquo;s not very easy to spot the areas consuming the most runtime.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a set of SQL statements to run against the ODI work repository tables to help you methodically find the steps of most interest for tuning efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two excellent OBI presentations from Jeff McQuigg</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/27/two-excellent-obi-presentations-from-jeff-mcquigg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/27/two-excellent-obi-presentations-from-jeff-mcquigg/</guid>
      <description>Jeff McQuigg has posted two presentations that he gave at Openworld 2010 on his website here: http://greatobi.wordpress.com/2010/10/26/oow-presos/
They&amp;rsquo;re full of real content and well worth a read. There&amp;rsquo;s excellent levels of detail and plenty to think about if you&amp;rsquo;re involved in OBI or DW development projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fair bite of the CPU pie? Monitoring &amp;amp; Testing Oracle Resource Manager</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/10/a-fair-bite-of-the-cpu-pie-monitoring-amp-testing-oracle-resource-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/10/a-fair-bite-of-the-cpu-pie-monitoring-amp-testing-oracle-resource-manager/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We&amp;rsquo;re in the process of implemention Resource Manager (RM) on our Oracle 11gR1 Data Warehouse. We&amp;rsquo;ve currently got one DW application live, but have several more imminent. We identified RM as a suitable way of - as the name would suggest - managing the resources on the server.
In the first instance we&amp;rsquo;re looking at simply protecting CPU for, and from, future applications. At some point it would be interesting to use some of the more granular and precise functions to demote long-running queries, have nighttime/daytime plans, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring real user response times for OBIEE</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/14/measuring-real-user-response-times-for-obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/06/14/measuring-real-user-response-times-for-obiee/</guid>
      <description>@alexgorbachev tweeted me recently after picking up my presentation on Performance Testing and OBIEE. His question got me thinking, and as ever the answer &amp;ldquo;It Depends&amp;rdquo; is appropriate here :-)
Why is the measurement being done? Without knowing the context of the work Alex is doing, how to measure depends on whether the measurement needs to be of: -
The actual response times that the users are getting, or The response times that the system is currently capable of delivering This may sound like splitting hairs or beard-scratching irrelevance, but it&amp;rsquo;s not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing and OBIEE</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/24/performance-testing-and-obiee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/24/performance-testing-and-obiee/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my presentation &amp;ldquo;Performance Testing and OBIEE&amp;rdquo; that I gave at the RittmanMead BI Forum 2010: Performance Testing and OBIEE.pptx
It&amp;rsquo;s a Powerpoint 2007 file (pptx) for which you may need the Microsoft PowerPoint Viewer 2007. I&amp;rsquo;ve included copious notes on each slide which hopefully cover the gist of what I talked about when I was delivering it. There are also a handful of funky animations which is why I&amp;rsquo;ve left it in pptx and not exported to PDF or other format (sorry Open Office users).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-13757: &#34;SQL Tuning Set&#34; &#34;string&#34; owned by user &#34;string&#34; is active.</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/09/ora-13757-sql-tuning-set-string-owned-by-user-string-is-active./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/09/ora-13757-sql-tuning-set-string-owned-by-user-string-is-active./</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with SQL Tuning Sets, and was trying to clear up my mess.
To list all the tuning sets: [sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;sql&amp;rdquo;] SET WRAP OFF SET LINE 140 COL NAME FOR A15 COL DESCRIPTION FOR A50 WRAPPED
select name,created,last_modified,statement_count,description from DBA_SQLSET [/sourcecode]
[sourcecode] NAME CREATED LAST_MODI STATEMENT_COUNT DESCRIPTION &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- sts_test_02 09-MAR-10 09-MAR-10 1 Test run 1 sts_test_01 12-FEB-10 12-FEB-10 1 an old STS test test test [/sourcecode]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIA 7.9.6 Performance Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/02/obia-7.9.6-performance-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/02/obia-7.9.6-performance-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>A new document has been published by Oracle, discussing ways of improving performance for OBIA 7.9.6 and 7.9.6.1. Its primary focus is around improving ETL performance. There&amp;rsquo;s some very interesting content including hardware sizing recommendations, and I&amp;rsquo;d strongly recommend anyone working with OBIA reads it.
It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;Oracle Business Intelligence Applications Version 7.9.6 Performance Recommendations&amp;rdquo; and is available on My Oracle Support through Doc ID 870314.1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brilliant performance articles by Cary Millsap</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/29/brilliant-performance-articles-by-cary-millsap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/01/29/brilliant-performance-articles-by-cary-millsap/</guid>
      <description>There is a LOT written about performance. And this post is now adding to it. Some of it&amp;rsquo;s excellent, some of it less so. But a lot of it starts from a point so far down the process that unless you know the first bit, you&amp;rsquo;re going to raring off and end up chasing your tail or p###ing in the wind&amp;hellip;. (pardon my french). Without a well structured approach that you understand and always follow you&amp;rsquo;ll hit on solutions by luck only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition on Sun Systems</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/12/deploying-oracle-business-intelligence-enterprise-edition-on-sun-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/12/deploying-oracle-business-intelligence-enterprise-edition-on-sun-systems/</guid>
      <description>A very interesting new PDF from Sun on deploying OBIEE has been published, with discussions on architecture, performance and best practice.
This Sun BluePrints article describes an enterprise deployment architecture for Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition using Sun servers running the Solaris Operating System and Sun Storage 7000 Unified Storage systems. Designed to empower employees in organizations in any industry—from customer service, shipping, and finance to manufacturing, human resources, and more—to become potential decision makers, the architecture brings fault tolerance, security, resiliency, and performance to enterprise deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New OBIEE benchmark - 50,000 users</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/12/new-obiee-benchmark-50000-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/12/new-obiee-benchmark-50000-users/</guid>
      <description>A new OBIEE benchmark has been published by Oracle. It&amp;rsquo;s on the same hardware as August&amp;rsquo;s benchmark - Sun T5440s. Anyone would think that Oracle like Sun ;-)
Details here
Numbers added to my collation post here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and HP Performance Center (a.k.a. LoadRunner) - Notes</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/obiee-and-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/obiee-and-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner-notes/</guid>
      <description>This is a supplemental post to this one describing how to set up a VUser in LoadRunner to test OBIEE. It&amp;rsquo;s various notes that I made during the development but which aren&amp;rsquo;t directly part of the step-by-step tutorial. They&amp;rsquo;re not necessarily vital for recording scripts, but observations and explanations that should be helpful when working with LoadRunner and OBIEE.
Validation using sawserver logs It&amp;rsquo;s no use running a load test if the load you think you&amp;rsquo;re applying isn&amp;rsquo;t actually being applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing OBIEE using HP Performance Center (a.k.a. LoadRunner)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/</guid>
      <description>My two earlier posts (here and here) detail the difficulties I had with LoadRunner (now called HP Performance Center). After a bit of a break along with encouragement from knowing that it must be possible because it&amp;rsquo;s how Oracle generates their OBIEE benchmarks I&amp;rsquo;ve now got something working. I also got a useful doc from Oracle support which outlines pretty much what I&amp;rsquo;ve done here too.
In essence what you do - and what the Metalink document 496417.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Morle : Spotting the Red Flags (Part 1 of n)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/25/james-morle-spotting-the-red-flags-part-1-of-n/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/25/james-morle-spotting-the-red-flags-part-1-of-n/</guid>
      <description>A new blog from James Morle, who I don&amp;rsquo;t know but from other bloggers sounds well respected, and describes himself thus:
Since it’s been nearly ten years since I wrote my book, Scaling Oracle8i, I thought it was about time that I started writing again. I thought I would start with the new-fangled blogging thing, and see where it takes me. Here goes.
He&amp;rsquo;s got a really interesting post on &amp;ldquo;red flags&amp;rdquo; to look for in diagnosing performance problems in Oracle: Spotting the Red Flags (Part 1 of n).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collated OBIEE benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/18/collated-obiee-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/18/collated-obiee-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>(Updated 12th Oct 09)
Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the OBIEE benchmark documents published by Oracle:
BenchmarkDateSource document1 - IBM System x3755Sep-07PDF2 - HP DL380 G4Sep-07PDF3 - Sun T2000Sep-07PDF4 - Sun SPARC Enterprise T5440Aug-09PDF5 - Sun SPARC Enterprise T5440Oct-09PDF Collecting the numbers into one table gives this: Based on the details in the documents I think these were all against OBIA&amp;rsquo;s Service Analytics schema &amp;amp; dashboards/reports.
Interesting to note the side-by-side comparison in benchmark 3 (Sun T2000) of two servers, in one case both running BI and Presentation Services and in the other having the two components separate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/17/obiee-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/17/obiee-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the OBIEE benchmark documents published by Oracle:
28,000 User Benchmark on Sun SPARC Enterprise T5440 Server running Solaris 10 [Aug 09]
10,000 User Benchmark on Sun T2000 [Sept 07]
5,800 User Benchmark on HP DL380 G4 [Sept 07]
4,000 User Benchmark on an IBM System x3755 Server running Red Hat Enterprise Linux</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE cluster controller failover in action</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/15/obiee-cluster-controller-failover-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/09/15/obiee-cluster-controller-failover-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Production cluster is 2x BI Server and 2x Presentation Services, with a BIG-IP F5 load balancer on the front.
Symptoms Users started reporting slow login times to BI. Our monitoring tool (Openview) reported that &amp;ldquo;BIServer01 may be down. Failed to contact it using ping.&amp;rdquo;. BIServer01 cannot be reached by ping or ssh from Windows network.
Diagnostics nqsserver and nqsclustercontroller on BIServer01 was logging these repeated errors:
[nQSError: 12002] Socket communication error at call=send: (Number=9) Bad file number</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and Load Runner - part 2</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/obiee-and-load-runner-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/21/obiee-and-load-runner-part-2/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED: See a HOWTO for OBIEE and LoadRunner here: /2009/10/01/performance-testing-obiee-using-hp-performance-center-a.k.a.-loadrunner/
This is following on from my first post about OBIEE and LoadRunner, in which I failed dismally to get a simple session replaying.
In a nutshell where I&amp;rsquo;d got to was using the &amp;ldquo;Web (Click and Script)&amp;rdquo; function which worked fine for logging in but when running a report resulted in an error on the rendered page. Digging around showed the error was from the javascript of the OBIEE front end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE and Load Runner - part 1</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/obiee-and-load-runner-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/19/obiee-and-load-runner-part-1/</guid>
      <description>UPDATED: See a HOWTO for OBIEE and LoadRunner here
Introduction LoadRunner is a tool from HP (bought from Mercury) that can be used to simulate user activity. It supports a whole host of protocols but for OBIEE I&amp;rsquo;m obviously using the Web one.
There are two flavours, &amp;ldquo;Web (Click and Script)&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Web (HTTP/HTML)&amp;rdquo;. The latter simply shoves HTTP requests at the server, whereas &amp;ldquo;Click and Script&amp;rdquo; simulates mouse and keyboard entry and thus is more appropriate for this user-based application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE performance monitoring and alerting with jManage</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/29/obiee-performance-monitoring-and-alerting-with-jmanage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/29/obiee-performance-monitoring-and-alerting-with-jmanage/</guid>
      <description>OBIEE&amp;rsquo;s Systems Management component exposes configuration and performance data through Java MBeans. As discussed in other posts these can be be accessed through several different ways:
JConsole (see also here) oc4j Windows PerfMon (although I guess this isn&amp;rsquo;t actually using MBeans/JMX?) saw.dll?perfmon BI Management Pack Since it&amp;rsquo;s a standard java technology being used we can in theory use anything that is designed for monitoring mbeans via jmx. Doing some Googling I discovered jManage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE Windows PerfMon counters</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/24/obiee-windows-perfmon-counters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/24/obiee-windows-perfmon-counters/</guid>
      <description>Yet another way to access the BI Management data discussed here - through Windows&amp;rsquo; PerfMon tool.
This will only work for installations where your OBIEE server is running on Windows. You should be able to run PerfMon locally or remotely. Standard practise would be not to run it locally on a Production machine :-)
To run PerfMon go to Start-&amp;gt;Run and enter perfmon, or navigate Start -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Control Panel -&amp;gt; Administrative Tools -&amp;gt; Performance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle BI Management / Systems Management MBeans</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/22/oracle-bi-management-/-systems-management-mbeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/22/oracle-bi-management-/-systems-management-mbeans/</guid>
      <description>Part of looking at the various gubbins inside OBIEE led me to realise that the Oracle BI Management application drives quite a few things. It exposes MBeans (Management Beans, a java term), accessible through jmx. In the installation of OBIEE this component is referred to as &amp;ldquo;Systems Management&amp;rdquo;.
The MBeans give us real-time performance information, along with access to all the configuration options that are normally done through config files (instanceconfig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JConsole / JMX - followup</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/jconsole-/-jmx-followup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/jconsole-/-jmx-followup/</guid>
      <description>A few points to add to my previous posting on JConsole:
As well as performance data, you have access to configuration data. Be aware that it is read-write! So whilst it might be a nice alternative to digging around for your instanceconfig.xml etc, you should be careful If you have your BI Server and Presentation Services deployed on separate servers then you will only get MBeans for the relevant service: If you want to view the values of the BI Server MBeans and your Presentation Services server is not on the same box then you have to use JConsole/JMX, as Performance Monitor will not have access to the values: ](http://2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIEE admin tools &amp;amp; hacks</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/obiee-admin-tools-amp-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/21/obiee-admin-tools-amp-hacks/</guid>
      <description>As a kid I loved the idea of lego where you can disassemble and reassemble something from the ground up. As soon as I got my hands on a computer it was the same. You can have your Acorn Archimedes with its games, where do I find the sprites and sound files behind it? Likewise Microsoft Word, let me at the VBA underneath to hack it around and see what else it can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JConsole / JMX</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/16/jconsole-/-jmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/16/jconsole-/-jmx/</guid>
      <description>[edit] See this post too [/edit] On an OBIEE server run [sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;] nohup obiee/systemsmanagement/runagent.sh &amp;amp; [/sourcecode] and then run jconsole (make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve set the DISPLAY first if you&amp;rsquo;re running it from UNIX). NB: if you don&amp;rsquo;t have jconsole in your path you can search for it: [sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;] $whereis jconsole jconsole: /opt/java1.5/bin/jconsole /opt/java6/bin/jconsole&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; [/sourcecode] You should find it under your java/bin directory
You should get this kind of connection dialog: Click connect, and the console will launch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
