<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>replicator on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/replicator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in replicator on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:55:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/replicator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Confluent Cloud when there is no Cloud (or internet)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2020/04/20/using-confluent-cloud-when-there-is-no-cloud-or-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:55:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2020/04/20/using-confluent-cloud-when-there-is-no-cloud-or-internet/</guid>
      <description>☁️Confluent Cloud is a great solution for a hosted and managed Apache Kafka service, with the additional benefits of Confluent Platform such as ksqlDB and managed Kafka Connect connectors. But as a developer, you won’t always have a reliable internet connection. Train, planes, and automobiles—not to mention crappy hotel or conference Wi-Fi. Wouldn’t it be useful if you could have a replica of your Cloud data on your local machine? That just pulled down new data automagically, without needing to be restarted each time you got back on the network?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resetting a Consumer Group in Kafka</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2019/08/09/resetting-a-consumer-group-in-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:32:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2019/08/09/resetting-a-consumer-group-in-kafka/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using Replicator as a powerful way to copy data from my Kafka rig at home onto my laptop’s Kafka environment. It means that when I’m on the road I can continue to work with the same set of data and develop pipelines etc. With a VPN back home I can even keep them in sync directly if I want to.
 I hit a problem the other day where Replicator was running, but I had no data in my target topics on my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
