<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>obia on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/obia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in obia on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/obia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When is a bug not a bug? When it&#39;s a &#34;design decision&#34;</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/18/when-is-a-bug-not-a-bug-when-its-a-design-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/10/18/when-is-a-bug-not-a-bug-when-its-a-design-decision/</guid>
      <description>Last month I wrote about a problem that Informatica as part of OBIA was causing us, wherein an expired database account would bring Oracle down by virtue of multiple connections from Informatica.
I raised an SR with Oracle (under OBIA support), who after some back-and-forth with Informatica, were told:
This is not a bug. That the two error messages coming back from Oracle are handled differently is the result of a design decision and as such not a product fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misbehaving Informatica kills Oracle</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/02/misbehaving-informatica-kills-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/02/misbehaving-informatica-kills-oracle/</guid>
      <description>This problem, which in essence is bad behaviour from Informatica bringing down Oracle, is a good illustration of unintended consequences of an apparently innocuous security setting. Per our company&amp;rsquo;s security standards, database passwords expire every 90 days. When this happens users are prompted to change their password before they can continue logging into Oracle. This applies to application user IDs too. It appears that Informatica 8.6.1 HF6 (part of OBIA 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating EBS-BI authentication, without BI</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/17/validating-ebs-bi-authentication-without-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/05/17/validating-ebs-bi-authentication-without-bi/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting EBS-BI integrated authentication can be a tiresome activity, so here&amp;rsquo;s a shortcut that might help. If you suspect the problem lies with EBS then you can leave OBIEE out of the equation.
Login to EBS
Use FireBug or Fiddler2 to inspect web traffic as follows:
Click the BI link from EBS
Should be first a request to EBS server, which returns 302 and redirects to http://&amp;lt;bi server&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/analytics/saw.dll?Dashboard&amp;amp;acf=101507310
Record the value of acf (eg 101507310)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIA 7.9.6 Performance Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/02/obia-7.9.6-performance-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/03/02/obia-7.9.6-performance-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>A new document has been published by Oracle, discussing ways of improving performance for OBIA 7.9.6 and 7.9.6.1. Its primary focus is around improving ETL performance. There&amp;rsquo;s some very interesting content including hardware sizing recommendations, and I&amp;rsquo;d strongly recommend anyone working with OBIA reads it.
It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;Oracle Business Intelligence Applications Version 7.9.6 Performance Recommendations&amp;rdquo; and is available on My Oracle Support through Doc ID 870314.1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I think this summarises everything.</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/27/i-think-this-summarises-everything./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/11/27/i-think-this-summarises-everything./</guid>
      <description>Why did this make me think of the OBIA upgrade documentation?? ;-)
via I think this summarizes everything..
[Update December 18, 2013: The lady in the picture is Kathy Sierra]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIA 7.9.6.1 released</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/12/obia-7.9.6.1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/10/12/obia-7.9.6.1-released/</guid>
      <description>The latest point release of Oracle Business Intelligence Applications, 7.9.6.1, has been released and is available for download from here (direct link to download).
The version.txt reports the version as:
Build: 7.9.6.1.100609.2038 Release Version: Oracle Business Intelligence Applications 7.9.6.1 Package: 100609.2038
No updated documentation library yet through, so can&amp;rsquo;t nosey through the release notes. The docs that come with the download are labelled 7.9.6 and dated April 09 so don&amp;rsquo;t look like they&amp;rsquo;ve been updated either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unix script to report on OBIEE and OBIA processes state</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/14/unix-script-to-report-on-obiee-and-obia-processes-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/14/unix-script-to-report-on-obiee-and-obia-processes-state/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a set of scripts that I use on our servers as a quick way to check if the various BI components are up and running.
Because we split the stack across servers, there are different scripts called in combination. On our dev boxes we have everything and so the script calls all three sub-scripts, whereas on Production each server will run one of:
BI Server Presentation Server &amp;amp; OAS Informatica &amp;amp; DAC The scripts source another script called process_check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIA upgrade 7.9.5 to 7.9.6 - first thoughts</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/13/obia-upgrade-7.9.5-to-7.9.6-first-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/13/obia-upgrade-7.9.5-to-7.9.6-first-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re upgrading from OBIA 7.9.5 (Financials - GL) to OBIA 7.9.6. Our reasons are for support (7.9.5 does not support Oracle 11g) and minor functionality additions.
Our architecture is: HP-UX 64 bit Itanium (11.31), Oracle 11g (11.1.0.7), separate ETL server, 4x OBIEE servers (2x BI, 2xPS). We have no customisations in the ETL except something for budgets, which is superseded in 7.9.6.
This post is a semi-formed articulation of my frustrations encountered during an initial run through of the upgrade in a sandbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repository Error ([REP_51821] Failed to connect from Integration Service (pmserver) to repository Oracle_BI_DW_Base running in exclusive mode.)</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/10/repository-error-rep_51821-failed-to-connect-from-integration-service-pmserver-to-repository-oracle_bi_dw_base-running-in-exclusive-mode./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/10/repository-error-rep_51821-failed-to-connect-from-integration-service-pmserver-to-repository-oracle_bi_dw_base-running-in-exclusive-mode./</guid>
      <description>I keep hitting this error when setting up OBIA. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s what it says on the tin, but Googling it didn&amp;rsquo;t match so I&amp;rsquo;m posting this so next time I hit it I remember :-)
Repository Error ([REP_51821] Failed to connect from Integration Service (pmserver) to repository Oracle_BI_DW_Base running in exclusive mode.)
The cause is the Repository Service having OperatingMode set to Exclusive. This is necessary for some of the setup operations like restoring the pre-built Repository, but if you forget to switch it back the Integration Service will suddenly stop working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OBIA grumble</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/04/obia-grumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/08/04/obia-grumble/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m starting on an upgrade from OBIA 7.9.5 to 7.9.6 and wading through the two main docs:
7.9.6 Upgrade guide 7.9.6 Installation guide It would be nice if Oracle could come up with some less confusing terminology. It seems that not only is the whole product of OBIA referred to as OBIA (see @lex&amp;rsquo;s posting for a good explanation), but that the sub-components which are not-OBIEE-or-DAC-or-Informatica is also OBIA, c.f. page 6-1 of the Upgrade guide &amp;ldquo;[&amp;hellip;]upgrade your Oracle BI Applications environment to the current version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is OBIA...</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/30/what-is-obia.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/07/30/what-is-obia.../</guid>
      <description>Very good post by @lex giving a nice clear explanation of what OBIA (Oracle Business Intelligence Applications) is
http://siebel-essentials.blogspot.com/2009/06/can-you-describe-oracle-bi-applications.html
This should be made a sticky on the OBIA forum in my opinion.
It&amp;rsquo;s clear from postings on the forum that an awful lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t understand what OBIA is or how it sits with OBIEE. I even attended a course last week in which the Oracle trainer stated that OBIEE included ETL and DW schemas, and stuck to this when challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New releases</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/28/new-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/04/28/new-releases/</guid>
      <description>New releases this week - 10.1.3.4.1 of OBIEE, and 7.9.6 of OBIA.
After a bit of scrabbling around found:
&amp;ldquo;The 10.1.3.4.1 release of the Oracle Business Intelligence Enterprise Edition introduces no new features.&amp;rdquo;
Though there are some new bits and pieces for Publisher
For 7.9.6 OBIA, there&amp;rsquo;s no New Features document :(
By piecing together the &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s New in This Release&amp;rdquo; for each document you can build up a picture (eg in the Upgrade Guide there&amp;rsquo;s reference to changes for the doc relating to a new version of Informatica), but it would be nice to have it all in one place:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORA-12537 / ORA-12518 [Informatica DAC error CMN_1022]</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/25/ora-12537-/-ora-12518-informatica-dac-error-cmn_1022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2009/03/25/ora-12537-/-ora-12518-informatica-dac-error-cmn_1022/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re getting problems with an instance of Informatica / out-of-the-box OBIA on a new set of servers. When we run the execution plan we get this error soon after starting:
MAPPING&amp;gt; DBG_21075 Connecting to database [TNSENTRY], user [MYUSER]
MAPPING&amp;gt; CMN_1761 Timestamp Event: [Tue Mar 24 18:56:33 2009]
MAPPING&amp;gt; CMN_1022 Database driver error&amp;hellip;
CMN_1022 [
Database driver error&amp;hellip;
Function Name : Logon
ORA-12537: TNS:connection closed
Database driver error&amp;hellip;
Function Name : Connect</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
