<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>visualisation on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</title>
    <link>https://rmoff.net/categories/visualisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in visualisation on rmoff&#39;s random ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmoff.net/categories/visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Labelling Time axes in Excel</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/09/08/labelling-time-axes-in-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/09/08/labelling-time-axes-in-excel/</guid>
      <description>Excel may send chills down the spine of us when we hear users talking about its [ab]use, but it has its place in the toolset. For my money, it is a very good tool for knocking out graphs which look decent. Of course, rrdtool is my geek tool of choice for dynamic long-term graphing, but when doing scratch PoC work, I normally fall back to Excel.
One thing which has frustrated me over time is, well, time, and Excel&amp;rsquo;s handling thereof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting good quality I/O throughput data</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/11/getting-good-quality-i/o-throughput-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/11/getting-good-quality-i/o-throughput-data/</guid>
      <description>This post expands on one I made last year here about sampling frequency (of I/O throughput, but it&amp;rsquo;s a generic concept). The background to this is my analysis of the performance and capacity of our data warehouse on Oracle 11g.
Before I get too boring, here&amp;rsquo;s the fun bit:
Pork Pies per Hour (PP/h) Jim wants to enter a championship pork-pie eating competition. He&amp;rsquo;s timed himself practising and over the course of an hour he eats four pork pies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny new geek toys -- rrdtool and screen</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/01/shiny-new-geek-toys-rrdtool-and-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2011/03/01/shiny-new-geek-toys-rrdtool-and-screen/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added two new toys to my geek arsenal today. First is one with which I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled before, but struggled to master. The second is a revelation to me and which I discovered courtesy of twitter.
rrdtool rrdtool is a data collection and graphing tool which I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of for a while. I wanted to use it when I wrote about Collecting OBIEE systems management data with JMX, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting OBIEE performance data with gnuplot</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/charting-obiee-performance-data-with-gnuplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/12/06/charting-obiee-performance-data-with-gnuplot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the second part of three detailed articles making up a mini-series about OBIEE monitoring. It demonstrates how to capture OBIEE performance information, and optionally graph it out and serve it through an auto-updating webpage.
This article takes data that part one showed you how to collect into a tab-separated file that looks something like this:
[sourcecode] 2010-11-29-14:48:18 1 0 11 0 3 2 1 676 340 0 53 1 0 41 0 3 0 2010-11-29-14:49:18 1 0 11 0 3 2 1 676 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 3 0 2010-11-29-14:50:18 2 0 16 1 4 3 1 679 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:51:18 2 2 19 1 4 3 1 679 32 0 53 1 0 58 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:52:18 2 1 19 1 4 3 4 682 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:53:18 2 1 19 1 4 3 4 682 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 2010-11-29-14:54:18 2 0 19 1 4 3 1 682 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 4 0 [/sourcecode]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A good maxim to bear in mind when designing reports</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/23/a-good-maxim-to-bear-in-mind-when-designing-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/09/23/a-good-maxim-to-bear-in-mind-when-designing-reports/</guid>
      <description>Jeff Atwood of Coding Horror fame observed:
This is sage advice (if a little crude :-)) to bear in mind when building reports for users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illustrating data</title>
      <link>https://rmoff.net/2010/02/08/illustrating-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rmoff.net/2010/02/08/illustrating-data/</guid>
      <description>In the following list, which two mind-mapping programs are rated best?
Now look at the actual numbers, and answer again Different answer?
I can&amp;rsquo;t be the only one in this frantic world whose eyes are drawn to the pictures instead of words and leap to conclusions. It&amp;rsquo;s only because I use FreeMind and was surprised it scored so low &amp;hellip;. and then realised it hadn&amp;rsquo;t. Looks like the HTML rendering isn&amp;rsquo;t the same here (FF3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
